<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<EventTranscript version="1.0.0" lastEdited="2004-01-30T22:03:52">
<EventID>836680</EventID>
<Notes>Power Systems
P: Steve McNeil;State Street Research;Analyst
C: Robert Johnson;Honeywell;President and CEO of Honeywell Aerospace
P: Moderator;;
P: Scott Davis;Morgan Stanley;Analyst
P: David Bleustein;UBS Warburg;Analyst
C: David Anderson;Honeywell;CFO
P: Paula Abbotts;;Analyst
C: David Cote;Honeywell;Chairman, CEO
P: Harriet Baldwin;Deutsche Bank Securities;Analyst
P: Tony Bowles;;Analyst
P: Don MacDougall;J.P. Morgan Chase;Analyst
C: Peter Kreindler;Honeywell;SVP, General Counsel
P: Howard Rubel;Soundview Technology Corp.;Analyst
P: Chuck Harris;;Analyst</Notes>
<Trans>
<Speakers>
<Speaker id="dangallagher" firstName="Dan" lastName="Gallagher" companyName="Honeywell" position="IR Director" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="rogerfradin" firstName="Roger" lastName="Fradin" companyName="Honeywell" position="President and CEO of Automation and Control Solutions" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="lizkind" firstName="Liz" lastName="Kind" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="unidentifiedaudiencemember" name="Unidentified Audience Member" identified="false" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="bobcornell" firstName="Bob" lastName="Cornell" companyName="Lehman Brothers" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="nancedicciani" firstName="Nance" lastName="Dicciani" companyName="Honeywell" position="President and CEO of Specialty Materials" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative" name="Unidentified Company Representative" identified="false" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="robgillette" firstName="Rob" lastName="Gillette" companyName="Honeywell" position="President and CEO of Transportation &amp; Power Systems" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="stevemcneil" firstName="Steve" lastName="McNeil" companyName="State Street Research" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="roberjohnson" firstName="Robert" lastName="Johnson" companyName="Honeywell" position="President and CEO of Honeywell Aerospace" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="moderator" name="Moderator" identified="false" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="scottdavis" firstName="Scott" lastName="Davis" companyName="Morgan Stanley" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="davidbleustein" firstName="David" lastName="Bleustein" companyName="UBS Warburg" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="davidanderson" firstName="David" lastName="Anderson" companyName="Honeywell" position="CFO" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="paulaabbotts" firstName="Paula" lastName="Abbotts" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="davidcote" firstName="David" lastName="Cote" companyName="Honeywell" position="Chairman, CEO" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="harribaldwin" firstName="Harriet" lastName="Baldwin" companyName="Deutsche Bank Securities" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="tonybowles" firstName="Tony" lastName="Bowles" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="donmacdougall" firstName="Don" lastName="MacDougall" companyName="J.P. Morgan Chase" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="peterkreindler" firstName="Peter" lastName="Kreindler" companyName="Honeywell" position="SVP, General Counsel" identified="true" organizer="true"/>
<Speaker id="howarrubel" firstName="Howard" lastName="Rubel" companyName="Soundview Technology Corp." position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
<Speaker id="chuckharris" firstName="Chuck" lastName="Harris" position="Analyst" identified="true" organizer="false"/>
</Speakers>
<Episode>
<Section type="report" name="presentation">
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="00:33:11" id="L0"/> Okay. <Sync time="00:33:12" id="L1"/> Please take a seat. <Sync time="00:33:13" id="L2"/> We will be starting up. <Sync time="00:33:16" id="L3"/> That's right, all you guys in the back come on. <Sync time="00:33:25" id="L4"/> Eli Lustgarden (ph) come on down. <Sync time="00:33:33" id="L5"/> Next up we have Roger Fradin, the new leader of our Automation and Control business.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="00:33:39" id="L6"/> Good afternoon. <Sync time="00:33:43" id="L7"/> I'm going to talk about how we did in '03. <Sync time="00:33:46" id="L8"/> Give you a heads up on how we're looking at '04. <Sync time="00:33:53" id="L9"/> Give you a lot more detail to support the growth initiatives that David described earlier, including how we're using productivity and a focus on cash to also fund growth. <Sync time="00:34:07" id="L10"/> <br/> If I look at the Automation and Control ACS portfolio I think many of you familiar with this business. <Sync time="00:34:16" id="L11"/> That is a $7.5 billion business. <Sync time="00:34:19" id="L12"/> Right now we talk about segment margins about 11 percent. <Sync time="00:34:21" id="L13"/> Just a little flavor there. <Sync time="00:34:23" id="L14"/> We consist of really a few major segments. <Sync time="00:34:27" id="L15"/> One is the products business that is about $4 billion. <Sync time="00:34:30" id="L16"/> And if you think about this portfolio, kind of a holistic perspective, at least how I do, in normal economy, this is a portfolio that I believe we can deliver organic growth in the 5 percent range. <Sync time="00:34:42" id="L17"/> That is my view of it. <Sync time="00:34:43" id="L18"/> <br/> If you take a look at the products part of this portfolio, which is about 4 billion, we are ready in general in pretty good space getting pretty good growth. <Sync time="00:34:54" id="L19"/> And our margins in the product part of the business are actually in the healthy double-digit range. <Sync time="00:34:59" id="L20"/> So a portfolio that is in reasonably good shape and pretty good growth space in Sensing, Fire and Security and emerging growth in the environmental and combustion controls business. <Sync time="00:35:11" id="L21"/> <br/> We also have a distribution business embedded in our product portfolio that is about $1 billion that earns normal distribution single digit margins. <Sync time="00:35:20" id="L22"/> And then we have two businesses that we are in the process of fixing. <Sync time="00:35:23" id="L23"/> So Dave and Dave shared with you some of the investments we are making in that business. <Sync time="00:35:27" id="L24"/> In those businesses one is the Process Solutions business, the HPS business, which actually I have a lot of good progress to report in '03. <Sync time="00:35:36" id="L25"/> And we're feeling pretty good about how we're doing. <Sync time="00:35:39" id="L26"/> We're fixing that business. <Sync time="00:35:40" id="L27"/> <br/> The Building Solutions business, we're a little bit earlier in the turnaround. <Sync time="00:35:45" id="L28"/> I have some good results to show in the back half of '03 setting us up for reasonable performance in '04. <Sync time="00:35:52" id="L29"/> <br/> As I look across this portfolio some things are in common. <Sync time="00:35:57" id="L30"/> Great brands. <Sync time="00:35:59" id="L31"/> Great brand presence, great installed base. <Sync time="00:36:02" id="L32"/> About 70 percent of our business comes out of our installed base today, which on the one hand is an opportunity, and on the other hand -- well it is an opportunity on both levels. <Sync time="00:36:13" id="L33"/> One is to do more business with our installed base, to increase the size of our installed base, which is a focus in Process Solutions and Building Solutions, and then to look outside of our traditional installed base to growth, the big focus area of the business. <Sync time="00:36:29" id="L34"/> <br/> We are global. <Sync time="00:36:33" id="L35"/> In the markets we play in technology wins. <Sync time="00:36:36" id="L36"/> And at its core we are a technology company. <Sync time="00:36:39" id="L37"/> So we have great technology presence, great customer relationships to build on. <Sync time="00:36:46" id="L38"/> <br/> Security and Fire is a business that we play in the products in that market. <Sync time="00:36:51" id="L39"/> Ditto for our Environmental and Combustion Control business, which is in the home comfort business, Building Automation business, in the Combustion Controls business. <Sync time="00:37:01" id="L40"/> Sensing and Controls business is also product play where we sell mainly to OEMs on a global basis. <Sync time="00:37:07" id="L41"/> <br/> In the Building Solutions business we play in the installation market, in the products market, the customer or environmental Combustion Controls products business. <Sync time="00:37:17" id="L42"/> But most significantly the reason we're in the installation business is to generate aftermarket service. <Sync time="00:37:24" id="L43"/> So there's a small profit earned on the installation, but big profits earned on the service piece. <Sync time="00:37:30" id="L44"/> So that is the real game here is to build the service bank. <Sync time="00:37:34" id="L45"/> <br/> In the Process Solutions, this is the one business where our customers tend to buy a total solution on a global basis. <Sync time="00:37:42" id="L46"/> So we're selling products, doing installations on a project basis and driving aftermarket revenue. <Sync time="00:37:50" id="L47"/> <br/> If I set the stage for you, let me take you back to the beginning of '03 in these businesses to share with you some of the challenges and the opportunities. <Sync time="00:37:59" id="L48"/> In the Process Solutions business we had investing to do. <Sync time="00:38:04" id="L49"/> We had just completed a year in investment, or two years of investment in '01 and '02 to develop a Next Generation process control platform for that business to really get back in the game and be competitive on lower total installed cost and winning new greenfield sites. <Sync time="00:38:23" id="L50"/> So at the beginning of '03 we were hopeful, but didn't yet have results to show in terms of getting uplift in orders. <Sync time="00:38:31" id="L51"/> <br/> In the Building Solutions business, it is a business, frankly, we are out of position in. <Sync time="00:38:35" id="L52"/> We have focused extensively on margin rates and that caused us to withdraw from the low margin installation business. <Sync time="00:38:44" id="L53"/> Well that set in motion kind of a downward cycle in that business. <Sync time="00:38:48" id="L54"/> As we stepped back from installations, we had natural attrition in our installed base, so the service bank started to deteriorate. <Sync time="00:38:55" id="L55"/> So that is a business where we have experienced a few years of year over year decline in sales and orders. <Sync time="00:39:02" id="L56"/> And we were setting about developing a turnaround plan for that business beginning of '03. <Sync time="00:39:07" id="L57"/> <br/> Also at the beginning of '03 our Environmental and Combustion Controls business, the thermostat business, Combustion Controls business, Building Automation business just was not doing a good job for our customers. <Sync time="00:39:19" id="L58"/> What Dave refers to in terms of the first pillar of growth, as doing a good job every day in terms of quality and delivery. <Sync time="00:39:25" id="L59"/> We were not delivering on time, and we had quality issues in that business. <Sync time="00:39:29" id="L60"/> So that was a turnaround that needed to happen. <Sync time="00:39:32" id="L61"/> <br/> Sensor and Control we had made a large and medium-sized acquisition in '02. <Sync time="00:39:39" id="L62"/> And we have a lot of integration work ahead of us in '03. <Sync time="00:39:42" id="L63"/> Our Security business was facing issues with Tyco, the largest customer in '03. <Sync time="00:39:47" id="L64"/> And our Fire business, which is driven off of commercial construction, was facing a downturn in the commercial construction market. <Sync time="00:39:54" id="L65"/> So with that year facing us, I'm very pleased to report how we did in '03. <Sync time="00:40:00" id="L66"/> In our Process Solutions business we just did a terrific job. <Sync time="00:40:04" id="L67"/> <br/> The Experion platform not only won a lot of kudos from industry pundits, we won a lot of new business. <Sync time="00:40:13" id="L68"/> So we sold 500 new systems, generated almost $900 million in new orders, and an orders growth rate that was significantly ahead of the market growth. <Sync time="00:40:24" id="L69"/> So as we come into '04, I am feeling very good about what we achieved in Process Solutions. <Sync time="00:40:30" id="L70"/> <br/> On the Building Solutions side, it was a year of putting together a strategy to get back in the game, and then beginning to execute on that strategy. <Sync time="00:40:39" id="L71"/> So the early half of the year was one of which of saying, hey, talking to our customers, figuring out how we're going to leverage our great name, our great installed base, lots of capabilities, and settle on the right strategy for the business. <Sync time="00:40:55" id="L72"/> <br/> And the strategy that we focused on is really to pick 20 key markets to invest in. <Sync time="00:41:01" id="L73"/> Remember I said this is a local business. <Sync time="00:41:03" id="L74"/> We need to be in the game with local relationships, winning on a local basis. <Sync time="00:41:08" id="L75"/> We recruited about 150 net news sales professionals for that business. <Sync time="00:41:13" id="L76"/> So we began to invest. <Sync time="00:41:15" id="L77"/> We invested in our services infrastructure, invested in the set of tools and processes to let us be lowest installed cost so that we can win on big day. <Sync time="00:41:25" id="L78"/> <br/> Now we had very strong results in Q4 in this business. <Sync time="00:41:29" id="L79"/> I will share those with you in a minute, double-digit orders growth. <Sync time="00:41:33" id="L80"/> So we have one strong quarter that sets us up for next year, but it is far too early to say, hey, we can declare victory in terms of the turnaround. <Sync time="00:41:42" id="L81"/> <br/> Our Environmental and Combustion Controls business in a year just did a spectacular job. <Sync time="00:41:48" id="L82"/> Organic growth in this business completely turned around our delivery and quality issues. <Sync time="00:41:56" id="L83"/> So strong improvement in deliveries, big improvement in quality, invested heavily in new product development pipeline. <Sync time="00:42:03" id="L84"/> Didn't have any new products to speak of in '03. <Sync time="00:42:06" id="L85"/> Have a lot of exciting new products queued up for '04. <Sync time="00:42:11" id="L86"/> <br/> Our Sensor and Control business I think became the poster child for following the new acquisition playbook that was referenced earlier. <Sync time="00:42:19" id="L87"/> We did a very nice job, actually beating our commitments on both the Invensys Sensor integration and the Senotec integration. <Sync time="00:42:28" id="L88"/> So acquisition integration machine going on. <Sync time="00:42:31" id="L89"/> <br/> On the Security end, putting aside the Tyco effect, that business actually grew double-digits in its non-Tyco business. <Sync time="00:42:42" id="L90"/> So a pretty good year for that business. <Sync time="00:42:44" id="L91"/> And the Fire business just had a spectacular year. <Sync time="00:42:47" id="L92"/> So in the face of a declining new construction market, that business grew north of 10 percent, actually 14 percent. <Sync time="00:42:55" id="L93"/> So nice growth in the Fire business. <Sync time="00:42:57" id="L94"/> <br/> So I think we're set up well for '04. <Sync time="00:42:59" id="L95"/> And if I look at some of the other key things we did in this portfolio, we made six key acquisitions, one small acquisition in the service business, the Building Solutions business. <Sync time="00:43:10" id="L96"/> And that was a small acquisition. <Sync time="00:43:12" id="L97"/> It gave us more contracting capacity in our energy retrofit business. <Sync time="00:43:16" id="L98"/> But more significantly, it sent a message to the employees and the customers that we're investing and we are back in the business. <Sync time="00:43:24" id="L99"/> So important from a signaling perspective. <Sync time="00:43:26" id="L100"/> <br/> Made a nice acquisition in the Fire business. <Sync time="00:43:29" id="L101"/> Acquired a company called, Gamewell. <Sync time="00:43:32" id="L102"/> It gave us another strong brand to add to our already strong Controls portfolio in that business. <Sync time="00:43:37" id="L103"/> A nice acquisition in Eastern Europe in our Security business to give us presence to grow from in that geography. <Sync time="00:43:45" id="L104"/> Two closed circuit television acquisitions. <Sync time="00:43:47" id="L105"/> And then a small, but very key acquisition in the structured wiring business, a company called FutureSmart, that makes structured wiring systems for new home construction. <Sync time="00:43:57" id="L106"/> This is a -- the reason it is a key acquisition, it lets us connect our Home Comfort business and our Security business to go to home builders, where we are we have a good relationship within the Home Comfort, side to sell them a complete package of Home Comfort products, home security products, and structured wiring. <Sync time="00:44:16" id="L107"/> Now that 70 percent, 70 percent plus of new homes get structured wiring. <Sync time="00:44:21" id="L108"/> So a very important acquisition for us. <Sync time="00:44:24" id="L109"/> <br/> In '03 we actually did not introduce a lot of new products in our product business. <Sync time="00:44:31" id="L110"/> We filled up that pipeline though and have many exciting new products coming out in '04. <Sync time="00:44:36" id="L111"/> So a lot of the results that I talked about in '03 really were not helped by new products because we didn't have any to ship during the year. <Sync time="00:44:46" id="L112"/> <br/> So in looking at '04 from the top-level perspective, we going to keep going with a momentum in the Process Solutions business, execute the turnaround plan in Building Solutions. <Sync time="00:44:58" id="L113"/> Lots of new products coming out across our product business on the Fire aside with new controls, new detection devices. <Sync time="00:45:05" id="L114"/> Entering a new submarket there, it is called Power Supplies, which are a fairly large and growing market that we have not been a strong player in. <Sync time="00:45:13" id="L115"/> Digital video market, new recording technology, new transmission technology, and some new high-end cameras in that business. <Sync time="00:45:21" id="L116"/> <br/> Sensing market, you will see medical sensors, new automotive sensors and even some sensors that are going to play on cellular phones. <Sync time="00:45:30" id="L117"/> In Environmental Combustion business at the back half of the year we're coming out with a whole new family of thermostats to really reinvigorate that very key legacy Honeywell product. <Sync time="00:45:42" id="L118"/> <br/> Last year was our first year of -- first full year of operations of our new Asia-Pacific business unit based in Shanghai. <Sync time="00:45:50" id="L119"/> Strong management team, focused on the China, Korea and Japanese markets primarily. <Sync time="00:45:56" id="L120"/> That business actually beat its plan. <Sync time="00:45:59" id="L121"/> And the job of the Asia Pacific SBU is to pull together all the services, solutions and products of the ACS portfolio, localize for those markets and drive growth in that region. <Sync time="00:46:11" id="L122"/> <br/> We will continue to focus on on-time delivery. <Sync time="00:46:14" id="L123"/> A personal focus of mine is sales and marketing excellent. <Sync time="00:46:17" id="L124"/> Using velocity product development, we're going to ramp up the rate at which we bring out new products, so same engineering resources will let us deliver more new products to the market. <Sync time="00:46:29" id="L125"/> <br/> If I look at our portfolio, I can't help but be very excited and encouraged by it. <Sync time="00:46:36" id="L126"/> About $2.5 billion of our 7.5 billion in this business is already in attractive space from both a growth rate and a margin rate perspective. <Sync time="00:46:49" id="L127"/> And we have nice plans to keep accelerating the growth in those businesses. <Sync time="00:46:54" id="L128"/> We have another approximately 2.5 billion of our portfolio in space that has strong margins, but historically has not delivered strong growth. <Sync time="00:47:04" id="L129"/> Again, we have some strong growth plans for those businesses. <Sync time="00:47:07" id="L130"/> So looking to move more of that portfolio up into the upper right quadrant. <Sync time="00:47:12" id="L131"/> And then we've got the Building Solutions business that right now we're in the midst of a turnaround. <Sync time="00:47:19" id="L132"/> <br/> The markets we plan play in, roughly $100 billion space. <Sync time="00:47:23" id="L133"/> Think of us as having high single digit share of that market. <Sync time="00:47:26" id="L134"/> So a lot of room for us to spread our wings and grow. <Sync time="00:47:29" id="L135"/> They're fundamentally good markets. <Sync time="00:47:31" id="L136"/> And if you look at our orders rate in '03 compared to what we believe the long-term growth rates are of those markets, not bad performance. <Sync time="00:47:41" id="L137"/> <br/> A personal priority for me is to instill and drive a growth culture across this portfolio. <Sync time="00:47:51" id="L138"/> And fundamentally it boils down to people, customers and driving sales excellent. <Sync time="00:47:57" id="L139"/> So for starters the test that I apply to the business to see if we have a growth culture is, do we have leaders in place in terms of general managers, sales and marketing and technology leaders who have a growth mindset and growth experience? <Sync time="00:48:13" id="L140"/> And as I look across this portfolio, we are in very good shape there. <Sync time="00:48:17" id="L141"/> <br/> The functionalized organization just gives our leaders more time to spend on new products, with customers, and on issues that drive growth, because our functional organizations are well-positioned to take care of the back room, infrastructure, delivery and quality, IT, finance, etc. <Sync time="00:48:39" id="L142"/> So the functionalized organization gives our leaders more growth bandwidth. <Sync time="00:48:43" id="L143"/> We've got top talent leaders in our sales and marking groups. <Sync time="00:48:47" id="L144"/> <br/> And a couple of key headset changes are taking place in this business. <Sync time="00:48:52" id="L145"/> One is the legacy Honeywell businesses just did a wonderful job servicing the existing customer base. <Sync time="00:48:58" id="L146"/> That was great. <Sync time="00:48:60" id="L147"/> However, didn't put a lot of focus on winning new customers, moving into adjacent space. <Sync time="00:49:06" id="L148"/> For example, compensation programs for our salespeople were heavily fixed. 70 to 80 percent of the compensation was fixed, a small amount was variable. <Sync time="00:49:17" id="L149"/> To me the signal of a growth oriented organization of winning business from the competition or moving into adjacent space is a much larger percentage of the compensation being variable. <Sync time="00:49:28" id="L150"/> And that is where we're going and moving towards the 50-50 type structure. <Sync time="00:49:32" id="L151"/> So focus on winning new business. <Sync time="00:49:35" id="L152"/> <br/> And another focus on just upgrading rating our sales and marketing capabilities across the business in terms of just contemporary tools to do market research, more understanding of our customers, more understanding of our competition so we have the right new products and services that our customers want to buy. <Sync time="00:49:56" id="L153"/> This may sound like a trite statement, but the way I characterize it is, we need to be one company focused on taking care of our customers. <Sync time="00:50:04" id="L154"/> In other words, everybody's sells, from the person who answers the phone, to the person who collects the bills, to the worker on the factory floor, has to think of themselves as part of sales, as part of one company serving the customer. <Sync time="00:50:18" id="L155"/> And that is a headset we're looking to drive across the business. <Sync time="00:50:21" id="L156"/> <br/> Now just by the way, in terms of how you grow, one of the key ways that you grow is you don't shrink. <Sync time="00:50:28" id="L157"/> In other words, in our service businesses our attrition rates are more than they ought to be. <Sync time="00:50:36" id="L158"/> So the first way to grow in the Process Solutions business and the Building Solutions business is defend our existing base. <Sync time="00:50:42" id="L159"/> So that is growth area No. 1. <Sync time="00:50:44" id="L160"/> Growth area No. 2 is, of course, new products, new services to capture more of the market. <Sync time="00:50:51" id="L161"/> <br/> So now let's take a look at some of our businesses. <Sync time="00:50:54" id="L162"/> The Process Solutions business is really just a wonderful business in a wonderful position. <Sync time="00:50:59" id="L163"/> We have the largest installed base, $15 billion installed base. <Sync time="00:51:03" id="L164"/> We are -- there is a little boasting, but I believe we the number one project delivery and execution company in the business. <Sync time="00:51:12" id="L165"/> Ninety-eight percent on time, on budget delivery, best safety record. <Sync time="00:51:18" id="L166"/> So a process oriented business can count on us to get them up and running on-time, so they don't miss a day of production. <Sync time="00:51:26" id="L167"/> That is a major competitive advantage. <Sync time="00:51:28" id="L168"/> <br/> Our safety record also takes a back seat to no one, also driving -- that is linked in delivering projects on time. <Sync time="00:51:39" id="L169"/> Strong service organization. <Sync time="00:51:40" id="L170"/> About a third of our revenue comes from service, the largest service organization in the business. <Sync time="00:51:46" id="L171"/> About 75 percent of the people in this business are chemical engineers. <Sync time="00:51:50" id="L172"/> So a deep and rich process knowledge. <Sync time="00:51:53" id="L173"/> And if you look at the landscape here, you have Honeywell on the one hand that focuses on the entire process. <Sync time="00:52:01" id="L174"/> And our value proposition we take to the customers -- hey, we're going to help you drive 1, 2, 3 percent improvement in your process, in your capital infrastructure, because we look at optimizing your entire production process. <Sync time="00:52:15" id="L175"/> And Emerson, on the other hand, who is our major competitor in this space, has mainly focused on the field instruments and on the valves. <Sync time="00:52:23" id="L176"/> We believe that our process oriented focus and our open system architecture with key partnerships essentially say, hey, you want to buy Flow Serve valves, that's great. <Sync time="00:52:34" id="L177"/> We integrate with Flow Serve. <Sync time="00:52:37" id="L178"/> You want to buy Toner field instruments? <Sync time="00:52:39" id="L179"/> That's great. <Sync time="00:52:39" id="L180"/> We integrate with them. <Sync time="00:52:40" id="L181"/> So we believe that our best in breed approach really is going to be a winner. <Sync time="00:52:45" id="L182"/> And by the way we were rewarded handsomely from the market last year with very strong growth. <Sync time="00:52:51" id="L183"/> <br/> So if I look at our opportunities going into '04, we are going to do more with Experion. <Sync time="00:52:57" id="L184"/> Experion is going to get more foundation field bus functionality. <Sync time="00:53:01" id="L185"/> We are going to continue to invest to give our legacy installed base a stronger migration path. <Sync time="00:53:10" id="L186"/> We have more value added services. <Sync time="00:53:12" id="L187"/> Better connectivity with ERP systems. <Sync time="00:53:14" id="L188"/> A big area, by the way, if you ask our customers in this space, what is the number one area they are interested in, it is security. <Sync time="00:53:22" id="L189"/> Well, guess what, that is our sweet spot pretty much across the board. <Sync time="00:53:26" id="L190"/> So we think we're very well-positioned to win our unfair share of industrial security spending. <Sync time="00:53:35" id="L191"/> <br/> We already do, by the way, about $300 million of business in what you call emerging regions in India, China, Russia, Eastern Europe. <Sync time="00:53:46" id="L192"/> That is where all the greenfield investment is going on. <Sync time="00:53:49" id="L193"/> So we have a very good structure, and with Experion now, a very good product platform to win in that space. <Sync time="00:53:56" id="L194"/> In addition, Experion no only because of its scalability, because of its small footprint lets us win in new space. <Sync time="00:54:04" id="L195"/> So for example, offshore oil platforms or liquid natural gas carriers, areas that Honeywell was traditionally not strong, partly because our system had a pretty big physical footprint. <Sync time="00:54:16" id="L196"/> And physical space is at a premium on an offshore oil rig. <Sync time="00:54:20" id="L197"/> Experion now has the smallest footprint in the business. <Sync time="00:54:23" id="L198"/> And we're now starting to win offshore oil rigs, Conoco, for example and L&amp;G carriers. <Sync time="00:54:28" id="L199"/> So good vertical market expansion. <Sync time="00:54:33" id="L200"/> And we are also well-positioned to expand in the pharmaceutical business, which is another vertical market that we have historically not been strong in. <Sync time="00:54:41" id="L201"/> <br/> Next slide please. <Sync time="00:54:43" id="L202"/> This is pictorially -- lets you see where we're focused on expanding in the HPS base. <Sync time="00:54:50" id="L203"/> First is to modernize our existing base, give them an upgrade path, Second is to focus on new vertical markets that Experion lets us go into, along with our PKS partnership advantage, oil and gas, power, pharmaceuticals. <Sync time="00:55:05" id="L204"/> Expand globally, build on an our already strong presence in the emerging regions. <Sync time="00:55:10" id="L205"/> And then add more value added services to the Experion offering, for example, ERP connectability. <Sync time="00:55:17" id="L206"/> That's what works. <Sync time="00:55:22" id="L207"/> <br/> On the Building Solutions side, this is a business about 2 billion in size. <Sync time="00:55:28" id="L208"/> Nice distribution between North America and the rest of the world. <Sync time="00:55:34" id="L209"/> In this business we install and service building automation systems. <Sync time="00:55:39" id="L210"/> We do mechanical maintenance and we do energy retrofit. <Sync time="00:55:43" id="L211"/> The bottom half of the chart, I think really shows you the situation pre-'03. <Sync time="00:55:50" id="L212"/> Then how we performed in '03, and how we're looking at '04. <Sync time="00:55:54" id="L213"/> So pre-'03 this is a business that was suffering declines in both orders and in revenue. <Sync time="00:56:00" id="L214"/> <br/> And the short story of the beginnings of our turnaround investments in '03 is reasonable performance, 9 percent growth in orders, very strong Q4 performance. <Sync time="00:56:11" id="L215"/> And this performance in Q4, 18 percent orders growth, sets us up to deliver Q1. <Sync time="00:56:17" id="L216"/> And we're investing, as you saw from Dave's chart earlier, in Q1 to keep driving the rest of year. <Sync time="00:56:25" id="L217"/> So the message is, we're back in the game here on the install side. <Sync time="00:56:31" id="L218"/> <br/> Next slide please. <Sync time="00:56:33" id="L219"/> Looking to build the service side. <Sync time="00:56:35" id="L220"/> And this is a year where we really need to execute on our turnaround plan. <Sync time="00:56:39" id="L221"/> I think many of you have seen this chart before. <Sync time="00:56:42" id="L222"/> And I'm not going to go through every bullet on here. <Sync time="00:56:44" id="L223"/> The message here is these are the four key areas we identified we needed to fix. <Sync time="00:56:50" id="L224"/> Improve product offerings. <Sync time="00:56:52" id="L225"/> We hadn't had any product or service offerings -- new offerings in this business -- in quite some time. <Sync time="00:56:57" id="L226"/> Improve our installation process. <Sync time="00:56:60" id="L227"/> Take our cycle time and Six Sigma know-how, apply it to the installation process to take out nonvalue added labor, so we can be the lowest installed cost and win our share of bids on bid day. <Sync time="00:57:11" id="L228"/> Improve our aftermarket service capability, so we responded on-time to emergency calls, responded promptly when customers called us to schedule a service, did preventative maintenance on-time, just the basics. <Sync time="00:57:25" id="L229"/> And finally, develop a stronger integrated systems platform with EDI. <Sync time="00:57:30" id="L230"/> <br/> So let me share with you just two of the new product offerings we have coming out in this business. <Sync time="00:57:35" id="L231"/> And I'm not going to stand up here and represent that either one is going to be grand slam for this business. <Sync time="00:57:41" id="L232"/> But they send some very key messages, one, to the customer base that, hey, Honeywell is back with some new and innovative offerings. <Sync time="00:57:48" id="L233"/> Number two, they energize our sales organization, because they have something new to sell. <Sync time="00:57:54" id="L234"/> <br/> So the first one is we call instant alert. <Sync time="00:57:56" id="L235"/> It is focused on the school market. <Sync time="00:57:59" id="L236"/> Education is a vertical market we have historically done very well in. <Sync time="00:58:03" id="L237"/> We have great relationships with school districts. <Sync time="00:58:06" id="L238"/> Do a lot of energy retrofit and security work there. <Sync time="00:58:09" id="L239"/> This is another product offering, service offering that we can take to the school district, tie-in with security that they can use for emergency notification of parents when there is an issue in the school. <Sync time="00:58:23" id="L240"/> <br/> So the economics here are pretty simple. <Sync time="00:58:26" id="L241"/> For $15 a month per student, and we sell the school district, they will have a web site they can do to to send out a notice to the parents, however the parent wants to be communicated with. <Sync time="00:58:39" id="L242"/> Whether it is email, whether it is pager, whether it is cell phone, they can get out a single broadcast on school closings or other issues. <Sync time="00:58:51" id="L243"/> So this is an offering we're just rolling out. <Sync time="00:58:53" id="L244"/> And we believe not only that we will be successful year, we will be able to broaden this service offering. <Sync time="00:59:01" id="L245"/> <br/> On the building side, and this integrates very nicely with our EDI, so it is another bolt on. <Sync time="00:59:06" id="L246"/> This is an asset tracking set tracking system to be used not only for assets in a commercial building, but if you think of babies as assets in a hospital, this system also lets you match up the right baby with the right mother in a hospital environment. <Sync time="00:59:22" id="L247"/> And the nice thing is that this completely integrates with our enterprise building integrator platform, so that all the alarms and all the information from this system is seamlessly and transparently integrated with the overall building management system. <Sync time="00:59:41" id="L248"/> <br/> Shifting gears into our product businesses, let's start off with the Sensor space, because we've spent a lot of time in the past talking about sensors. <Sync time="00:59:49" id="L249"/> Why do we like sensors? <Sync time="00:59:50" id="L250"/> Really three reasons. <Sync time="00:59:52" id="L251"/> One the space is very large. <Sync time="00:59:55" id="L252"/> Number two, it is growing. <Sync time="00:59:57" id="L253"/> And the dynamics causing its gross are really right in Honeywell's sweet spot. <Sync time="01:00:03" id="L254"/> And number three, we are very well-positioned, in fact independent industry experts would place Honeywell as the number one supplier in the world in sensors, when you add what Bob does in the aerospace sensing business, and what I do with the ACS businesses. <Sync time="01:00:18" id="L255"/> <br/> So let me give you one example of why we're so excited about sensors. <Sync time="01:00:23" id="L256"/> One of the key areas that we do very well in is automotive sensors. <Sync time="01:00:26" id="L257"/> You may say, hey, gee that is not so exciting. <Sync time="01:00:28" id="L258"/> The number of cars built every year is roughly flat. <Sync time="01:00:31" id="L259"/> However, if you have acquired a new car recently, the number of sensors on that car is up 10X from last generation's car, and probably 100X from a few generations ago. <Sync time="01:00:45" id="L260"/> So the number of sensors per car is exploding. <Sync time="01:00:49" id="L261"/> And that -- not only is that the story in the automobile industry, it is the story in the aerospace industry, and a lot of other industries that we're positioned to play in. <Sync time="01:00:58" id="L262"/> <br/> So let's take a look at our sensor business. <Sync time="01:01:00" id="L263"/> We really have four main business units within that business. <Sync time="01:01:04" id="L264"/> What we call automotive -- I'm sorry the automotive business, the ATOM business, which is aerospace, transport, ordnance and marine, and industrial business and a commercial business. <Sync time="01:01:16" id="L265"/> Some of our fundamental strength stems from the fact that we're married together with a terrific aerospace business. <Sync time="01:01:22" id="L266"/> And if you think about sensing applications, the most demanding applications really come out of aerospace. <Sync time="01:01:28" id="L267"/> And what I have the ability to do is take that terrific technology and commercialize it to address the CTQs of the commercial customers, typically starting with the automotive customers, then industrial, then commercial, then consumer. <Sync time="01:01:42" id="L268"/> This typically is as the degree of difficulty goes. <Sync time="01:01:46" id="L269"/> So great access to a technology portfolio. <Sync time="01:01:49" id="L270"/> <br/> Deep application know-how. <Sync time="01:01:51" id="L271"/> Fifty years this business has been part of Honeywell solving very difficult customer problems. <Sync time="01:01:58" id="L272"/> Again, another automobile example, we sell a cam and crank sensor today that is embedded in an automobile engine, so it withstands the heat, the pressure, the EMI from being inside that engine. <Sync time="01:02:11" id="L273"/> It tells the engine management system the position of the cram and crank shaft, so it knows when to fire the spark plugs to minimize exhaust gases. <Sync time="01:02:21" id="L274"/> So this particular trend in this particular product is driven by environmental trends. <Sync time="01:02:25" id="L275"/> As Dave talked about earlier, more and more environmental regulations. <Sync time="01:02:29" id="L276"/> So deep application know-how during the hard stuff. <Sync time="01:02:33" id="L277"/> So great legacy there. <Sync time="01:02:35" id="L278"/> <br/> Operational excellence. <Sync time="01:02:37" id="L279"/> It is a core CTQ to play in this business. <Sync time="01:02:40" id="L280"/> Many of our factories in this business make millions of sensors a year, zero defect, actually running at 7 Sigma. <Sync time="01:02:47" id="L281"/> Great pipeline of new technologies and a Best-in-class acquisition playbook, that really is going to be a competitive advantage to this business. <Sync time="01:02:56" id="L282"/> So we are aggressive on getting the cost synergies. <Sync time="01:02:59" id="L283"/> We don't lose sight of the sales synergies. <Sync time="01:03:01" id="L284"/> We move very quickly on the cultural integration. <Sync time="01:03:05" id="L285"/> And we use a best-in-class integration approach in terms of making sure we keep the best people from the businesses we acquire and marry them up with the best Honeywell people. <Sync time="01:03:16" id="L286"/> <br/> So what is this business missing? <Sync time="01:03:19" id="L287"/> A focus on sales and marketing. <Sync time="01:03:20" id="L288"/> This business has historically been focused on great technology and operational excellence, less focused on let's go win some new market share. <Sync time="01:03:29" id="L289"/> So we have a growth minded leader, ten year GE experience, seven year entrepreneurial business building experience. <Sync time="01:03:37" id="L290"/> The name is Ron Sampson. <Sync time="01:03:38" id="L291"/> Been in place about six months. <Sync time="01:03:40" id="L292"/> A best-in-class sales manager, new to the business. <Sync time="01:03:43" id="L293"/> So growth oriented leadership is in place. <Sync time="01:03:46" id="L294"/> <br/> David Cote last year drove a cross Honeywell sensor initiative (technical difficulty) there are opportunities across the Honeywell portfolio to share sensor technology. <Sync time="01:04:01" id="L295"/> I bet you won't be surprised to learn that there are all sorts of opportunities for me to sell sensors to Bob in the Aerospace business and Rob in the Turbo business. <Sync time="01:04:10" id="L296"/> Their products that are being outs by outside today, I have that technology in-house today. <Sync time="01:04:14" id="L297"/> A $100 million sales opportunity for my business looking out next several years. <Sync time="01:04:20" id="L298"/> Looking to build our presence in Automotive. <Sync time="01:04:23" id="L299"/> High-growth sensor spaces, medical and even consumer. <Sync time="01:04:26" id="L300"/> And this is a rich area for us from an acquisition perspective. <Sync time="01:04:32" id="L301"/> <br/> Next slide place, please. <Sync time="01:04:34" id="L302"/> Environmental Combustion Controls business, as I said earlier, is really four different businesses. <Sync time="01:04:39" id="L303"/> One is our core Home Comfort business. <Sync time="01:04:42" id="L304"/> A great installed base. <Sync time="01:04:43" id="L305"/> Installed in about 100 million homes globally, well known, well respected brand. <Sync time="01:04:49" id="L306"/> We have a Building Automation business. <Sync time="01:04:51" id="L307"/> Number one installed base, installed in about 5 million buildings. <Sync time="01:04:56" id="L308"/> We have a Combustion Control business that as an outsider looking in, they would say this is a sleepy business. <Sync time="01:05:02" id="L309"/> I think this is a business rife with growth opportunities. <Sync time="01:05:05" id="L310"/> This is a market that we roughly share with Emerson on a global basis. <Sync time="01:05:09" id="L311"/> Where we supply the hard parts of a warm air furnace in North America, what is called a Combee boiler in Europe. <Sync time="01:05:18" id="L312"/> We make the gas valve, which is the most difficult part of the furnace to make, and all the control electronics. <Sync time="01:05:25" id="L313"/> <br/> The opportunity here is to embed more technology in the furnace side where we sell to OEMs, like Train and Lenox. <Sync time="01:05:33" id="L314"/> And we participate in the aftermarket, which is when it is a winter like this, and a lot of parts of the furnaces are breaking. <Sync time="01:05:40" id="L315"/> It is a nice opportunity for us. <Sync time="01:05:43" id="L316"/> Not a nice opportunity for you, if you're the one whose furnace breaks down. <Sync time="01:05:48" id="L317"/> So we have an opportunity to embed more technology in the furnace. <Sync time="01:05:52" id="L318"/> For example, wireless capabilities to enable more add-on sales downstream. <Sync time="01:05:57" id="L319"/> <br/> And the fourth part of this portfolio is a small part today, but it is an area we're really looking to invest and build upon. <Sync time="01:06:04" id="L320"/> And that is a water controls and water filtration. <Sync time="01:06:06" id="L321"/> So our growth priorities for '04 are to use technology to redefine the category. <Sync time="01:06:14" id="L322"/> And I think many of you have heard me give this example before. <Sync time="01:06:17" id="L323"/> But with we would love to tie together our home security business and our home comfort business. <Sync time="01:06:23" id="L324"/> But there are two industries that really don't play well together at the homeowner. <Sync time="01:06:28" id="L325"/> We have HVAC contractors and security contractors. <Sync time="01:06:31" id="L326"/> And they don't work together with the homeowner. <Sync time="01:06:33" id="L327"/> So the question is, how do we tie these systems together so that when you have a Honeywell home alarm system installed and a Honeywell home comfort system thermostat installed, one equals 3, without those two industries cooperating. <Sync time="01:06:48" id="L328"/> <br/> Now the way to do that is wireless. <Sync time="01:06:50" id="L329"/> So we are embedding wireless capabilities in our next generation thermostats and home alarm systems to allow these systems to work together. <Sync time="01:06:58" id="L330"/> For example, when you have a Honeywell alarm and you turn your system on a way, it will automatically set back your thermostat. <Sync time="01:07:03" id="L331"/> So for free, you'll get an energy-saving advantage. <Sync time="01:07:07" id="L332"/> Another advantage -- idea using wireless is, I have a wireless remote control. <Sync time="01:07:12" id="L333"/> I'm in my den and I want to make it 70 degrees in my den. <Sync time="01:07:16" id="L334"/> Well, I've got to go to my hall thermostat today and fiddle with the temperature to get it the right temperature in the den. <Sync time="01:07:22" id="L335"/> Wouldn't it be nice to have a device that I can just that the temperature, and it is 70 degrees in the den. <Sync time="01:07:27" id="L336"/> That is a product we are working on. <Sync time="01:07:29" id="L337"/> <br/> Wouldn't it be nice to go up to my thermostat and know what the outdoor air temperature is? <Sync time="01:07:34" id="L338"/> If I had a wireless outdoor temperature sensor that connected seamlessly to my thermostat in the house, that I bought Home Depot at retail so I can install it myself, -- so this is the flavor of the type of add-on sales that we're trying to come up with to redefine this category. <Sync time="01:07:52" id="L339"/> <br/> On the Combustion perspective, we see more and more opportunities to save our OEMs money and drive more growth for Honeywell by embedding more and of the technology of the furnace in core Honeywell products. <Sync time="01:08:07" id="L340"/> So a lot of new products coming out on that end in terms of manifolds and electronic control systems. <Sync time="01:08:13" id="L341"/> Investing in building the brand. <Sync time="01:08:17" id="L342"/> So this is not only -- this is a licensing play plus a brand building play to help get our name out there and create pull for both the Home Comfort channel and the Security channel. <Sync time="01:08:29" id="L343"/> In this business alone, by the way, we have 35 new product launches planned for next year for '04. <Sync time="01:08:35" id="L344"/> So this is a business that historically has not had a lot of new products. <Sync time="01:08:39" id="L345"/> We have a whole new line of thermostats, new building automation products, and a whole new range of combustion products coming out. <Sync time="01:08:47" id="L346"/> <br/> So let's talk about Security and Fire. <Sync time="01:08:50" id="L347"/> Same questions for sensors -- or same opportunities for sensors. <Sync time="01:08:53" id="L348"/> It is a very big space with good fundamental underlying growth. <Sync time="01:08:59" id="L349"/> And we're very well-positioned to play here. <Sync time="01:09:01" id="L350"/> If I look at the segments, I have the classic intrusion alarms segment lime segment, the burglar alarm segment. <Sync time="01:09:06" id="L351"/> We are the number one player in that segment. <Sync time="01:09:09" id="L352"/> I have the access control segment of the market, although it is fragmented. <Sync time="01:09:13" id="L353"/> Honeywell is the number one player. <Sync time="01:09:15" id="L354"/> And the closed circuit television business, which with some of our acquisitions in organic growth, we are were improving our position. <Sync time="01:09:21" id="L355"/> And we have ambitions to be one of the top couple of players. <Sync time="01:09:25" id="L356"/> <br/> On the fire alarm side, we are one of the top four players in the world on the control side. <Sync time="01:09:30" id="L357"/> And we're the number one supplier of smoke detectors. <Sync time="01:09:34" id="L358"/> So unlike the process automation business, where there are more and more there is a trend towards open systems, and we're well-positioned to capitalize on that trend, in the fire alarm world which is heavily code driven, the open system world hasn't yet taken root, and shows no sign of taking root, which is great for Honeywell, because we have such a large installed proprietary close date. <Sync time="01:09:57" id="L359"/> You have a Honeywell fire system installed. <Sync time="01:10:00" id="L360"/> You pretty much have to buy a Honeywell product for all your adds, moves and changes. <Sync time="01:10:05" id="L361"/> <br/> From a technology perspective, not only are those three areas critical in terms of wireless systems integration and sensors, I would add a fourth called communication. <Sync time="01:10:16" id="L362"/> And without exception, we're the leader in the technology world in this business. <Sync time="01:10:23" id="L363"/> If I look at the business, strong dealer base, great legacy track record of developing new products, of being aggressive on the sales and marketing side. <Sync time="01:10:33" id="L364"/> In terms of where we're looking to grow in '04, really turn up the volume by digital video closed circuit television business. <Sync time="01:10:41" id="L365"/> And it was called the DVR business, the digital video recorder business. <Sync time="01:10:45" id="L366"/> The transmission of video signal business, lots of growth opportunity. <Sync time="01:10:49" id="L367"/> <br/> On the integrated systems side, more and more looking to bring together our access control systems, our security systems, our TV and our fire alarm systems into an integrated package, and pursue the large systems market. <Sync time="01:11:02" id="L368"/> This is a market that historically is about $1 billion space. <Sync time="01:11:06" id="L369"/> Historically this business has not been particularly effective in. <Sync time="01:11:09" id="L370"/> As part of Honeywell now with both the global presence, the brand, and the technology we're well-positioned to win in the large system space. <Sync time="01:11:20" id="L371"/> So think about airports, think about large industrial complexes. <Sync time="01:11:25" id="L372"/> <br/> We have a gas detection line that we're poised to come out with. <Sync time="01:11:29" id="L373"/> I just want to use that as an example of a trend that we're trying to drive. <Sync time="01:11:36" id="L374"/> In past presentations you have heard me talk about moving from sensors having core sensing technology, using that as a competitive advantage in products, and then using that to create a competitive advantage in systems. <Sync time="01:11:48" id="L375"/> Here we have developed what I believe is best-in-class next generation gas detection technology. <Sync time="01:11:55" id="L376"/> Core gas sensing technology that we're going to embed in a product -- it is called a smoke detector. <Sync time="01:12:03" id="L377"/> But really we will use gas sensing as a way that we're going to detect a fire. <Sync time="01:12:07" id="L378"/> So it is going to be an early warning smoke detector, a best-in-class smoke detector that hopefully will be a game changer in that market. <Sync time="01:12:16" id="L379"/> So core sensing technology is going to let us drive a competitive advantage in products, and when integrated with our fire alarm system, will give us a system advantage. <Sync time="01:12:24" id="L380"/> So that is how we're thinking about the sensing market, not only in terms of the opportunities of the sensing market, but the ability to leverage that technology right across our portfolio. <Sync time="01:12:36" id="L381"/> <br/> Just a flavor of the new products we're introducing not only in Security and Fire business, on the digital video side. <Sync time="01:12:44" id="L382"/> On the S&amp;C Sensing and Control business, we've got some great medical products coming out, pressure sensors, fluid flow sensors, using mems (ph) technology. <Sync time="01:12:54" id="L383"/> Transmission speed sensors to enable new drive by wire technology coming out in cars. <Sync time="01:12:60" id="L384"/> A terrific new tire pressure sensor where we partnered with the world's largest manufacturer of commercial tires to allow them to embed in their tires a pressure sensor to manage the lifecycle of the tires that they lease. <Sync time="01:13:16" id="L385"/> <br/> And last but not least, there are a couple of terrific new offerings coming out on the Experion platform. <Sync time="01:13:21" id="L386"/> Wireless sensors, wireless field devices. <Sync time="01:13:24" id="L387"/> We will be the first major player in the Process Solutions business with a wireless offering, introducing that next quarter. <Sync time="01:13:31" id="L388"/> And then a mobile monitoring wireless platform to allow to the process engineer to walk around the refinery, for example, and get all his metrics online without having to go back to home base. <Sync time="01:13:44" id="L389"/> <br/> Embedded in our Security and Fire business, and I mentioned this at the beginning of the presentation, is a great business called AVI, a distribution business. <Sync time="01:13:52" id="L390"/> So in our Security and Fire business we not only manufacture products, we control the channel to market. <Sync time="01:13:60" id="L391"/> I think I am able to say that, Peter. <Sync time="01:14:02" id="L392"/> I gave Peter a little heartburn. <Sync time="01:14:05" id="L393"/> <br/> This is a business that has well north of 50 percent share in the market. <Sync time="01:14:12" id="L394"/> We have 100 branches that a contractor will sell you a home alarm tonight, wearing a suit. <Sync time="01:14:18" id="L395"/> Come into our AVI store in his overalls the next day and buy all parts they need for an alarm system. <Sync time="01:14:24" id="L396"/> So terrific customer intimacy with our contractors, where we not only sell them all the Honeywell products they need for that installation, but all the accessories products, including those made by our competitors. <Sync time="01:14:37" id="L397"/> <br/> To build on Dave's point about how we're using productivity to step up our growth rate, cycle time is a major initiative. <Sync time="01:14:49" id="L398"/> And this is not an original quote, but inventory I have heard defined as the distance between us and our customers. <Sync time="01:14:57" id="L399"/> We have too much inventory today, too much distance between us and our customers. <Sync time="01:15:01" id="L400"/> The focus of our cycle time initiatives is to do a better job with delivery, with less inventory. <Sync time="01:15:08" id="L401"/> And lots of good stuff going on across the business in terms of the relationship with our suppliers, the way we design products. <Sync time="01:15:15" id="L402"/> <br/> For example in our Environmental and Combustion Control products business today, our cycle time to make electronic thermostats in the factory today, believe it or not, is five days. <Sync time="01:15:25" id="L403"/> All designs. <Sync time="01:15:26" id="L404"/> The new designs have cycle times in the factories of five minutes. <Sync time="01:15:30" id="L405"/> So a big focus on factory cycle times. <Sync time="01:15:33" id="L406"/> Big focus on rationalizing our distribution infrastructure, particularly in Europe. <Sync time="01:15:37" id="L407"/> It is just cumbersome in terms of the way we service our customers. <Sync time="01:15:41" id="L408"/> So lots of good projects going on that side. <Sync time="01:15:44" id="L409"/> <br/> We are applying cycle time to new product development cycle. <Sync time="01:15:47" id="L410"/> We call it DPD, or velocity product development. <Sync time="01:15:50" id="L411"/> Looking for a big bite this year to improve our ability, our speed to market by about 15 percent, and more to follow in '05. <Sync time="01:15:59" id="L412"/> Sales and marketing excellence, a lot going on here. <Sync time="01:16:04" id="L413"/> National accounts function has created -- we have created that at the ACS levels. <Sync time="01:16:08" id="L414"/> It reports directly to me. <Sync time="01:16:10" id="L415"/> The objective here is to look for opportunities to drive business across ACS. <Sync time="01:16:16" id="L416"/> <br/> For example, home builders. <Sync time="01:16:18" id="L417"/> We want to take a package of offerings to our home builders to get them to specify Honeywell home comfort products, security products, structured wiring products. <Sync time="01:16:28" id="L418"/> We want to take a package of offerings to large companies like Honeywell, like IBM, like Boeing to get them to specify Honeywell for their building automation systems in their facilities, building service in their facilities, fire and security. <Sync time="01:16:44" id="L419"/> Looking to go to big box retailers, specify Honeywell fire, Honeywell automation, Honeywell service. <Sync time="01:16:50" id="L420"/> So looking to pull in from across the ACS portfolio to drive additional business. <Sync time="01:16:56" id="L421"/> <br/> I mentioned building the brand. <Sync time="01:16:59" id="L422"/> Developing world-class sales and marketing, a personal priority. <Sync time="01:17:03" id="L423"/> Making sure we have the right people, properly incented, proper comp programs, get them focused on winning new business. <Sync time="01:17:09" id="L424"/> Pricing excellence is a big deal. <Sync time="01:17:11" id="L425"/> We have all sorts of opportunity to not only improve our sales, but improve our profitability just in the way we manage price. <Sync time="01:17:19" id="L426"/> We have a formal process that we piloted last year with good results in our thermostat business. <Sync time="01:17:25" id="L427"/> And we're rolling that across the ACS portfolio. <Sync time="01:17:28" id="L428"/> <br/> Localizing marketing talent. <Sync time="01:17:30" id="L429"/> We talk about China. <Sync time="01:17:31" id="L430"/> We talk about Russia. <Sync time="01:17:33" id="L431"/> We're not going to do the marketing for those countries from North America. <Sync time="01:17:36" id="L432"/> We are going to have best-in-class talent. <Sync time="01:17:38" id="L433"/> We have best-in-class talent in those geographies to drive the appropriate new products and new service offerings. <Sync time="01:17:45" id="L434"/> And finally, deploying a contemporary marketing tool kits to our marketing people, know how to segment our customers, and really understand why they buy from Honeywell, why they don't buy from Honeywell, and what they like about our competitors. <Sync time="01:18:01" id="L435"/> <br/> In closing, this is a good business with part of the portfolio already in good growth, good profit space. <Sync time="01:18:09" id="L436"/> Another part of the portfolio, the process solutions part, I believe we are making very good progress on our turnaround. more results to come in '04. <Sync time="01:18:17" id="L437"/> And we're still working on completely fixing our Building Solutions business.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="01:18:24" id="L438"/> Thank you, Roger. <Sync time="01:18:25" id="L439"/> We only have time for just a couple of questions.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="01:18:28" id="L440"/> I know you guys had lunch together, so I hope you didn't set this up.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="lizkind"><Sync time="01:18:39" id="L441"/> Liz Kind (ph), Roger. <Sync time="01:18:40" id="L442"/> I guess I'm just wondering based on the fundamental markets that you outlined and the orders growth that you showed in 2003, in each of the markets, I would expect the revenue growth for '04 to be probably in the 5 percent range at a minimum, just based on what you outlined for the market growth for each of the businesses and what your orders are?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="01:19:01" id="L443"/> A couple of points. <Sync time="01:19:02" id="L444"/> One is the orders growth has some FX in them. <Sync time="01:19:09" id="L445"/> Second, clearly I hope to do better than what we're committing to you. <Sync time="01:19:15" id="L446"/> So let me just leave it with those comments.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="01:19:22" id="L447"/> Roger, I know you weren't at the helm, but in 2001 and 2002 the emphasis in this segment was on restructuring. <Sync time="01:19:30" id="L448"/> There were massive layoffs. <Sync time="01:19:33" id="L449"/> And if I recall, we're talking about 400 basis points of margin improvements that was available there. 2003 went through a bit of recrimination. <Sync time="01:19:42" id="L450"/> Kevin, had held us, hey, we are starving the business. <Sync time="01:19:45" id="L451"/> We need to invest in growth. <Sync time="01:19:47" id="L452"/> So we are investing in growth, and it seems to be working. <Sync time="01:19:51" id="L453"/> But the margins are still bouncing around 11 to 12 percent. <Sync time="01:19:55" id="L454"/> <br/> Looking forward -- and I know there is spending. <Sync time="01:19:58" id="L455"/> There's some abnormally high spending on development and the growth initiatives this year. <Sync time="01:20:03" id="L456"/> But looking forward in '05, how do you balance growth versus margins? <Sync time="01:20:08" id="L457"/> And what do you think the long-term growth rate of this business is going to be? <Sync time="01:20:13" id="L458"/> And what do you think the margin opportunity is?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="01:20:15" id="L459"/> Terrific questions. <Sync time="01:20:16" id="L460"/> And let me just build on what Dave Anderson said earlier. <Sync time="01:20:20" id="L461"/> One is, we are investing. <Sync time="01:20:21" id="L462"/> So what you're seeing here is more salespeople, more feet on the street, more service people to rebuild the HBS business. <Sync time="01:20:28" id="L463"/> At the same time, we're getting more new installations. <Sync time="01:20:32" id="L464"/> <br/> In the Process Solutions business or the Building Solutions business, we're getting more new installations, and haven't yet realized the local benefits of the downstream service. <Sync time="01:20:42" id="L465"/> So bad impact on the margin mix. <Sync time="01:20:46" id="L466"/> Because we get low margins in the installation market, we haven't yet gotten to a steady state where we getting the aftermarket service from those new installations. <Sync time="01:20:54" id="L467"/> <br/> So we are investing to get the business. <Sync time="01:20:57" id="L468"/> And then we also have a higher mix of new installations. <Sync time="01:20:60" id="L469"/> So I think that is what we're going to see in '04. <Sync time="01:21:02" id="L470"/> As we look to go '05, 06 we are going to see a better balance of aftermarket service. <Sync time="01:21:06" id="L471"/> We know that it is going to come. <Sync time="01:21:08" id="L472"/> We are going to see a pickup in the product business, which has higher margins. <Sync time="01:21:11" id="L473"/> So as I said when I opened up, I believe this is a business in a normal economy that we're going to see about 5 percent organic growth.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="01:21:19" id="L474"/> Have you seen 15 percent margin business?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="01:21:24" id="L475"/> I don't see 15 percent in the next three years. <Sync time="01:21:27" id="L476"/> But I certainly see steady 1 point a year improvement, if I can say that.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="01:21:32" id="L477"/> Just two more. <Sync time="01:21:33" id="L478"/> These are great questions.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="01:21:36" id="L479"/> I guess first on process control. <Sync time="01:21:39" id="L480"/> You noted going after new verticals, certainly one of the first things that Experion seemed to do was firm up the installed base. <Sync time="01:21:47" id="L481"/> There is still I think some debate about whether or not you're winning your fair share or not in greenfield, but defending your installed base. <Sync time="01:21:54" id="L482"/> I'm just wondering on those 500 or so systems wins that you noted, what percent of those were installed base wins or expansions versus greenfield? <Sync time="01:22:04" id="L483"/> <br/> And then secondarily to that, and it might be a little bit to Quinn's question is, you mentioned really your great execution with the customer on some of those process project awards. <Sync time="01:22:16" id="L484"/> I think that has also been part of the margin problem with this company. <Sync time="01:22:19" id="L485"/> Maybe the company has bent over backwards for the customer and lost some of the economics in the project management side of things. <Sync time="01:22:27" id="L486"/> So if you could give us a little color on what is going on there, and what the opportunity might be?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="01:22:31" id="L487"/> It's a fair question. <Sync time="01:22:32" id="L488"/> The second question, I don't have enough experience in the business to give you an answer to the second question. <Sync time="01:22:36" id="L489"/> The first question I do know the answer to. <Sync time="01:22:38" id="L490"/> We have about 350 sales. <Sync time="01:22:41" id="L491"/> Of the 500 were to our existing base. <Sync time="01:22:44" id="L492"/> Roughly 150 were -- we would consider new wins.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="01:22:50" id="L493"/> Final question goes to Bob Cornell.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="bobcornell"><Sync time="01:22:51" id="L494"/> You know the old softball question. <Sync time="01:22:56" id="L495"/> You talked about putting more money -- in the Building Control business, the new building business, you talk about spending money to build up the infrastructure in 20 new markets. <Sync time="01:23:05" id="L496"/> What were the lead times between when you started to spend that money, but those people in the street, and when you started to get orders? <Sync time="01:23:12" id="L497"/> And what might we expect going forward?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="01:23:14" id="L498"/> Real good question, Bob. <Sync time="01:23:16" id="L499"/> Figure about three month's time between when you hire a new rep and have him trained up where they can start to get proposals out. <Sync time="01:23:23" id="L500"/> We started to invest in the end of the second quarter, beginning of third quarter. <Sync time="01:23:28" id="L501"/> So I think we saw some of that pop in the fourth quarter. <Sync time="01:23:31" id="L502"/> Does that answer you question? (inaudible) Yes, roughly. <Sync time="01:23:36" id="L503"/> Then it is about another --.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="01:23:41" id="L504"/> (inaudible)</Turn>
<Turn speaker="rogerfradin"><Sync time="01:23:42" id="L505"/> No, no, no, no. <Sync time="01:23:42" id="L506"/> I said 20 markets is our goal. <Sync time="01:23:44" id="L507"/> We actually are focused in about 12 markets, is where we made the investment. <Sync time="01:23:49" id="L508"/> So about 8 more to go in '04.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="01:23:52" id="L509"/> Thanks a lot, Roger. <Sync time="01:23:53" id="L510"/> Next up we have Nance Dicciani, the leader of our Specialty Materials business.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="nancedicciani"><Sync time="01:24:07" id="L511"/> Thank you, Dan. <Sync time="01:24:08" id="L512"/> And good afternoon everyone. <Sync time="01:24:11" id="L513"/> Last year at this meeting I told you that 2003 was going to be a transition year for Specialty Materials, and it was. <Sync time="01:24:22" id="L514"/> We also talked about the fundamental portfolio restructuring that was well underway at that time. <Sync time="01:24:29" id="L515"/> And we talked about some of the growth opportunities that we had in our core businesses. <Sync time="01:24:35" id="L516"/> And we have made progress on all fronts. <Sync time="01:24:38" id="L517"/> <br/> Our portfolio restructuring is almost complete. <Sync time="01:24:42" id="L518"/> And over the last year we have in our core businesses obtained organic growth rates that actually, not only last year but also in 2002, that surpassed most of the players in the chemical industry. <Sync time="01:24:56" id="L519"/> That is both U.S. and foreign. <Sync time="01:24:59" id="L520"/> So all in all, it has been a very busy, challenging and productive year for us. <Sync time="01:25:15" id="L521"/> <br/> Today we will start off with a bottom line look at our basic financials and some of the specifics that are behind them. <Sync time="01:25:24" id="L522"/> Then I will talk about the transformation activities that are already completed. <Sync time="01:25:30" id="L523"/> And several of them that are actually underway even as we speak. <Sync time="01:25:34" id="L524"/> I'll give you an update on our nylon business, which was the transaction that we completed with BASF last April. <Sync time="01:25:42" id="L525"/> This has been a very, very good deal for us. <Sync time="01:25:45" id="L526"/> And it has been a nice contributor, not only to 2003 results, but will be a big contributor to our year-over-year improvement in 2004. <Sync time="01:25:55" id="L527"/> <br/> Then we will look at some of the growth opportunities in selected growth platforms that we have, that I think you'll find exciting. <Sync time="01:26:05" id="L528"/> And these are the same growth platforms, or among those growth platforms that I talked about last year. <Sync time="01:26:11" id="L529"/> And all of them continue to be extreme extremely attractive. <Sync time="01:26:14" id="L530"/> <br/> Now I will close my remarks today with an outlook for 2004 for our business. <Sync time="01:26:22" id="L531"/> Our basic financials shown in the graph at the top of this slide underscore the fundamental transformation that has been occurring in the Specialty Materials portfolio. <Sync time="01:26:34" id="L532"/> Now keep in mind that these financials do not include the joint venture with Dow UOP -- do not include. <Sync time="01:26:41" id="L533"/> Over the past 18 months or so we have exited 8 businesses or product lines and 23 plants. <Sync time="01:26:52" id="L534"/> That was a net decrease in revenues of over $300 million. <Sync time="01:26:57" id="L535"/> All of that $300 million was fully recovered through organic growth in our core businesses. <Sync time="01:27:04" id="L536"/> And most importantly we gave up on low performing businesses in return for profitable growth. <Sync time="01:27:12" id="L537"/> The steady margin improvement came not only from this organic growth, but also from the synergies that we received from the nylon deal, as well as the continued focus on productivity and the use of Six Sigma, which is certainly a hallmark of Honeywell. <Sync time="01:27:30" id="L538"/> <br/> Now one of the tuck in acquisitions that we made was a small Korean films business, which also expanded our global reach. <Sync time="01:27:40" id="L539"/> Now this margin improvement year on year, and going forward certainly in 2003, was achieved in spite of about $100 million in raw material price increases, two very significant operational upsets in our plants, and as Dave Anderson mentioned earlier, one hurricane. <Sync time="01:28:03" id="L540"/> <br/> So let's look at a bit more in detail of the divestitures and acquisitions we made. <Sync time="01:28:09" id="L541"/> Certainly the biggest change in our portfolio in the last year was a business trade that we made with BASF. <Sync time="01:28:17" id="L542"/> We gave up a relatively small in plastics terms, relatively small U.S. space plastics business in return for cash and our nylon fibers business. <Sync time="01:28:28" id="L543"/> I am going to tell you a little bit more about how we're doing in that business in a moment. <Sync time="01:28:34" id="L544"/> <br/> As you can see, many of these divestitures were small. <Sync time="01:28:38" id="L545"/> But I think it is important to understand that even though they were small, they were cash drains. <Sync time="01:28:45" id="L546"/> They were financial drains on this business. <Sync time="01:28:47" id="L547"/> And they were drains on management attention as well. <Sync time="01:28:50" id="L548"/> The one acquisition that I have listed here is the Korean films business that I just mentioned, and that is in the food packaging area, and serves the North Asian market. <Sync time="01:29:01" id="L549"/> <br/> So as you can see, despite all of these acquisitions an divestitures, which made it a very busy year for us, the organic growth in our core businesses will result again in 2004 revenue that are going to be slightly up. <Sync time="01:29:18" id="L550"/> The strategic transformation of our Specialty Materials businesses is continuing. <Sync time="01:29:26" id="L551"/> So we're moving away from a cyclical, petroleum or natural gas based business. <Sync time="01:29:32" id="L552"/> When we talk about raw materials, those are the two that are at the foremost, the petroleum and the natural gas. <Sync time="01:29:39" id="L553"/> We're moving away from those businesses to a business which has steady growth and much more consistent financial performance, much less dependent on the raw material pricing swing. <Sync time="01:29:51" id="L554"/> <br/> Our volume driven commodity low growth product lines are slowing been replaced with technology-based and IP protected products that are focused on future oriented growth markets. <Sync time="01:30:05" id="L555"/> We added in the IT area just in the last year alone, we added 114 new patents and 191 new patent applications. <Sync time="01:30:15" id="L556"/> And also, we increased the percent of sales from new products to almost 30 percent just in the last year alone. <Sync time="01:30:22" id="L557"/> Pretty significant changes. <Sync time="01:30:24" id="L558"/> Now all of these new products, of course, are high-value, high-growth, and they all enjoy global market reach. <Sync time="01:30:34" id="L559"/> <br/> Now both Dave and Roger talked about a new operating environment within Honeywell. <Sync time="01:30:39" id="L560"/> And it is certainly the case in Specialty Materials. <Sync time="01:30:42" id="L561"/> The underlying the successful transformation of our business is a new operating environment. <Sync time="01:30:51" id="L562"/> We are much more functionalized and we're much more streamlined. <Sync time="01:30:54" id="L563"/> And in fact the short way to describe it is that this place has changed. <Sync time="01:30:60" id="L564"/> <br/> Technology, for example, has changed. <Sync time="01:31:03" id="L565"/> We have established a velocity product development process that both Dave and Roger have already talked about, which helps us not only understand the market needs better, but helps us get the products to the market much faster. <Sync time="01:31:17" id="L566"/> We have increased our R&amp;D spending in our core. <Sync time="01:31:20" id="L567"/> And we have also refocused and restaffed both our product applications and development efforts throughout the business. <Sync time="01:31:29" id="L568"/> <br/> On the globalization front, we're building a new applications laboratory in Shanghai, which will be fully operational by the middle of this year. <Sync time="01:31:38" id="L569"/> Which will also enable us to respond much more closely and quickly to our customers in the Asian market. <Sync time="01:31:46" id="L570"/> Operations have also changed. <Sync time="01:31:48" id="L571"/> You already heard from Roger and Dave about quality measurements on a daily basis and delivery on the basis of customer request, not negotiated, the customer request. <Sync time="01:31:58" id="L572"/> <br/> We have a new capital deployment process and cycle time reduction process that is not only going to take out the slack time that we've got in our systems, but it is also going to significantly improve our working capital. <Sync time="01:32:13" id="L573"/> These changes have also added focus and discipline, and also improves our operating performance across the board. <Sync time="01:32:22" id="L574"/> <br/> In addition to the increased functionalization in technology and operations, we have also added dedicated resources to commercial excellence, not only at the group level but also in our businesses. <Sync time="01:32:35" id="L575"/> These resources are focused on deriving full value for our products. <Sync time="01:32:42" id="L576"/> <br/> Now, I will discuss our core growth businesses shortly, but let me first talk about the remaining noncore businesses. <Sync time="01:32:53" id="L577"/> Our industrial wax business is based on petroleum. <Sync time="01:32:57" id="L578"/> Today, this business as a profitable, GDP growth-rate business. <Sync time="01:33:02" id="L579"/> We're running this business for cash and capitalizing on the strong position that we have based on our China plant. <Sync time="01:33:10" id="L580"/> <br/> Our polyester business, which produces tire for yarn and seat belts, is now in the process of being sold. <Sync time="01:33:18" id="L581"/> As with our wax business, polyester also has a fully utilized plant in China. <Sync time="01:33:25" id="L582"/> We expect this sale to be closed sometime during the second quarter of this year. <Sync time="01:33:29" id="L583"/> <br/> The nylon business, as most of you know, is a combination of the Honeywell nylon carpet fiber business and the nylon business that we acquired from BASF. <Sync time="01:33:41" id="L584"/> This business not only has a full range of branded and unbranded products that serve the residential, commercial and automotive markets, it also has an intermediates product line. <Sync time="01:33:55" id="L585"/> Now, the most significant product in this area is ammonium sulfate, which services the fertilizer market throughout the world. <Sync time="01:34:03" id="L586"/> We have a 3.3 billion pound ammonium sulfate business and are the world's largest producer. <Sync time="01:34:10" id="L587"/> It's a good business for us. <Sync time="01:34:13" id="L588"/> <br/> Now, the BASF and Honeywell nylon businesses -- again, we closed in April of last year. <Sync time="01:34:21" id="L589"/> Those were fully integrated in 90 days, to get to Dave Cote's point about our ability to fully integrate; we did that integration in 90 days. <Sync time="01:34:31" id="L590"/> All the expected synergies, which were cost synergies, have already been realized. <Sync time="01:34:37" id="L591"/> Now, we will continue to run this business until it's prudent to pursue a different strategic direction. <Sync time="01:34:47" id="L592"/> <br/> A couple more words about this business, though. <Sync time="01:34:52" id="L593"/> It serves the North American market, although we do have a plant in China. <Sync time="01:34:57" id="L594"/> This business today now has scale and low-cost. <Sync time="01:35:02" id="L595"/> Although the growth rate is essentially a GDP growth rate, today it's profitable, it's running well and it's getting better. <Sync time="01:35:13" id="L596"/> <br/> I've already mentioned the synergies we achieved. <Sync time="01:35:15" id="L597"/> Let's look at a couple of the other value drivers, quickly. <Sync time="01:35:21" id="L598"/> Now, aside from the recent three-year period, it's important to remember that this nylon business was a very good business for Allied and for Honeywell for a number of years. <Sync time="01:35:31" id="L599"/> The average industry margins are shown in this chart by the gray bars. <Sync time="01:35:37" id="L600"/> <br/> The last couple of years have been the worst in the history of the nylon business through a rather unfortunate combination of weak market demand, which was due to the economic capacity underutilization, natural gas prices that have been higher in the last couple of years than they've ever been by a factor of three and four, and also, a consolidation of downstream customers. <Sync time="01:36:04" id="L601"/> Now, keep in mind that natural gas is used as a raw material for this business. <Sync time="01:36:11" id="L602"/> <br/> We are now coming out of this trough and expect solid margin improvement over the next several years -- number one, due to the synergies that I just talked about that we realized in our deal; number two, we're running this business on a lot more streamlined and better way; number three, we have an increased demand for our branded products across the board; number four, we have improved capacity utilization because of some of the changes that we made in the BASF deal. <Sync time="01:36:39" id="L603"/> <br/> Any decrease in natural gas prices from where they are today will be additional upside for this business. <Sync time="01:36:50" id="L604"/> <br/> Now, let's turn our focus to our next slide, please, to our core growth businesses. <Sync time="01:36:58" id="L605"/> These are electronic materials, barrier solutions, Fluorines, advanced fibers and composites and reagents. <Sync time="01:37:08" id="L606"/> <br/> Now, our Fluorines business is a high growth, high margin business with all of the trends in our favor. <Sync time="01:37:15" id="L607"/> The increasing environmental regulations over the past several years have driven a major shift away from fluorocarbons or products that contain chlorine. <Sync time="01:37:27" id="L608"/> These are the CFCs in this chart -- moving toward products that contain less chlorine, which are the HCFCs -- that's an alphabet soup here -- continuing to drive to products that contain no chlorine, which are the HFCs. <Sync time="01:37:47" id="L609"/> We've shifted of our product line to suit this chain. <Sync time="01:37:50" id="L610"/> As you can see from this graph, the HFCs here shown in green are going to enjoy very, very high growth for the next several years. <Sync time="01:38:01" id="L611"/> Honeywell's years of research in developing technology in environmentally friendly products have positioned us very, very well and in fact, we are the worldwide leader in this segment. <Sync time="01:38:13" id="L612"/> So, the gradual phase-out of chlorine-containing products in this area will provide a very steady growth for our proprietary HFCs for years to come. <Sync time="01:38:25" id="L613"/> <br/> The other thing to keep in mind about this business is that we have already invested in our future. <Sync time="01:38:32" id="L614"/> We built two new plants and brought them onstream in the last 18 months. <Sync time="01:38:37" id="L615"/> We are now in a position to benefit not only from our strong patent position but all of those capital investments that we've made over the last couple of years. <Sync time="01:38:46" id="L616"/> <br/> So, not only do we have environmental legislation on our side, we have proprietary products and a growing dossier of patented applications as well. <Sync time="01:38:58" id="L617"/> Our proprietary HFCs not only provide higher value to our customers, they provide higher value to us. <Sync time="01:39:09" id="L618"/> <br/> The use of our products is expanding very rapidly, as refrigerants and as foam-blowing agents, for everything from roofing to insulation. <Sync time="01:39:20" id="L619"/> These products are non-ozone-depleting, they are nonflammable, they have a low toxicity, and they are energy efficient and they are growing at more than 10 percent per year. <Sync time="01:39:30" id="L620"/> <br/> Many of the opportunities -- the new opportunities we have are emerging in the area of medical applications and the manufacture of electronic complements and other high-tech areas. <Sync time="01:39:42" id="L621"/> <br/> It's been said that Fluorine is very small molecule with a very big ego, and that's true. <Sync time="01:39:48" id="L622"/> Because of the unique physical and chemical properties, fluorine use is growing everywhere and Honeywell is in a position to lead that growth. <Sync time="01:40:01" id="L623"/> <br/> One synergistic growth area for us with Fluorines is our electronic materials business. <Sync time="01:40:07" id="L624"/> It (indiscernible) Flourines to help the semiconductor manufacturers pack more power on a chip. <Sync time="01:40:14" id="L625"/> <br/> In addition to our fluorine products, we make a wide variety of other chemical and metal products for this high growth, fast-paced semiconductor arena. <Sync time="01:40:25" id="L626"/> Here again, advances in technology drive progress and in this area alone we have more than 500 issued patents and a lot of others in the works. <Sync time="01:40:36" id="L627"/> <br/> We're one of the top suppliers to the entire semiconductor industry and we are involved in almost every one of these layers in the chip. <Sync time="01:40:46" id="L628"/> We provide high purity metals for the circuits; you can see one of our copper sputtering targets outside in the vestibule here. <Sync time="01:40:53" id="L629"/> We have high purity chemicals to be used as etchants (ph). <Sync time="01:40:58" id="L630"/> We provide different kinds of thermal protection and heat protection for these products. <Sync time="01:41:03" id="L631"/> <br/> We are growing this business very, very rapidly in Asia with a new plant in Thailand and a customer support laboratory in Singapore. <Sync time="01:41:14" id="L632"/> <br/> Additionally, the semiconductor industry needs materials innovations, and we have very close working relationships with the leader in this industry in the areas of technology development. <Sync time="01:41:25" id="L633"/> I include companies like Intel and IBM and Texas Instruments. <Sync time="01:41:32" id="L634"/> <br/> Here is another terrific, profitable growth space for us -- advanced fibers and composites. <Sync time="01:41:40" id="L635"/> Now, the market for Spectra continues to expand. <Sync time="01:41:43" id="L636"/> Spectra is one of our products in this particular product line which is known for its use primarily in ballistic protection. <Sync time="01:41:52" id="L637"/> Our product is now being used in the interceptor vests worn by our Armed Forces in the Middle East and also by our law enforcement officers here at home. <Sync time="01:42:01" id="L638"/> We will also have some examples of this product out in the vestibule here. <Sync time="01:42:08" id="L639"/> <br/> Now, the use of Spectra fiber in these types of ballistics applications, whether they are helmets or vests, vehicles, blast-containment applications, have been growing so rapidly that we have been in a state of essentially constantly expanding over the last two years. <Sync time="01:42:27" id="L640"/> We see that continuing into the future -- a very high growth area for us. <Sync time="01:42:32" id="L641"/> <br/> Now, in addition to the broadening areas in security applications, our expertise in combining Spectra fiber with other products is also leading to some new opportunities for us in other applications where only things like steel or specialty materials have worked in the past -- (indiscernible) protection, mooring lines for ships, and drilling platforms and other types of cabling areas. <Sync time="01:43:01" id="L642"/> This is very high growth, again, a proprietary product for us. <Sync time="01:43:07" id="L643"/> <br/> The last platform that I will talk about today is our Barrier Solutions platform. <Sync time="01:43:13" id="L644"/> This one uses several products from the other businesses as raw materials, so again, we're building a very synergistic portfolio. <Sync time="01:43:21" id="L645"/> Our Aclar film is a fluorine-based product. <Sync time="01:43:25" id="L646"/> It's the best product available for pharmaceutical packaging, those clear, single-(indiscernible) packaging. <Sync time="01:43:31" id="L647"/> <br/> I don't know if anyone in the room knows this but there are more people who that die in this country each year from incorrect medication than from automobile accidents. <Sync time="01:43:41" id="L648"/> So, as we move forward with single-dose pharma packaging -- this is a very high growth area for our business. <Sync time="01:43:49" id="L649"/> <br/> Flexible food packaging is another area that's a high growth. <Sync time="01:43:52" id="L650"/> Most of us don't think about food packaging until we can't get into a package, but this is a very high growth area and our films business that we just bought in Korea is at the leading edge of food-packaging technology, and also, as I mentioned, serves the Asian market. <Sync time="01:44:08" id="L651"/> <br/> There are also many other high-end needs for moisture or oxygen or CO2 or other Barrier properties that our products provide. <Sync time="01:44:18" id="L652"/> Pharmaceuticals, food and beverages, electronics area -- in fact, I'm sure most of you have seen the Wall Street Journal this morning; there was an article in the second section here on illumination and there is another article down here on high-density televisions. <Sync time="01:44:37" id="L653"/> Now, in area of illumination, our films business is working with these companies to provide the kind of moisture barriers and oxygen sensitivity required for these applications. <Sync time="01:44:48" id="L654"/> <br/> Our electronic materials business is working with all of the leaders, Samsung, TI and so forth, in the high-definition television set. <Sync time="01:44:56" id="L655"/> That's just today's Wall Street Journal as an example of the kinds of things that we're doing and we're moving into in the specialty materials business. <Sync time="01:45:07" id="L656"/> So again, moving away from yesterday's chemistry and yesterday's technology to focus on future trends. <Sync time="01:45:14" id="L657"/> <br/> Now, our quick outlook for 2004 -- certainly, we're going to realize the full benefit of the very good deal we did with BASF. <Sync time="01:45:26" id="L658"/> We've got activities underway in each and every one of our businesses that are focused on providing value to our customers -- improved value to our customers -- and obtaining margin improvements in return. <Sync time="01:45:39" id="L659"/> <br/> We will continue to expand our reach with a new fluorine-blending facility that we're going to be putting in Asia sometime by the end of this year, the beginning of next year. <Sync time="01:45:50" id="L660"/> We are going to continue to push best practices across the entire specialty materials portfolio through functionalization in streamlining what we do. <Sync time="01:46:01" id="L661"/> Our new applications lab in Shanghai, as I mentioned, will be fully operational by the middle of this year, and we're going to continue to refine our portfolio further. <Sync time="01:46:12" id="L662"/> <br/> The external environment for our business appears more positive than it has in the past three years. <Sync time="01:46:18" id="L663"/> Demand for our products, specifically (indiscernible) products, are picking up. <Sync time="01:46:22" id="L664"/> Our feedstock costs in 2004 are expected to be stable, although high. <Sync time="01:46:29" id="L665"/> Our capacity utilization for our products will continue to improve. <Sync time="01:46:34" id="L666"/> <br/> We had a great end to 2003, very, very strong finish with, as Dave Anderson mentioned, 8 percent growth, and it is certainly our expectation that we will deliver in 2004. <Sync time="01:46:46" id="L667"/> <br/> Thank you for your attention. <Sync time="01:46:49" id="L668"/> I think we have -- (Multiple Speakers).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="01:46:50" id="L669"/> Time for just a couple of questions. <Sync time="01:46:52" id="L670"/> We're going to try to spread it out a little bit. <Sync time="01:46:55" id="L671"/> We will go left and right. <Sync time="01:46:58" id="L672"/> Don?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="01:46:60" id="L673"/> A couple of questions, Nance. <Sync time="01:47:06" id="L674"/> First, on the pricing environment with the past utilization creeping up, raw material costs stable, the other dimension is price. <Sync time="01:47:15" id="L675"/> Do you expect the market to be tight enough to get price? <Sync time="01:47:19" id="L676"/> <br/> The second question would be on the fluorocarbon investment that you've been doing for the past several years. <Sync time="01:47:26" id="L677"/> If you could maybe talk about the swing factor on getting some revenues associated with those investment dollars in 2004?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="nancedicciani"><Sync time="01:47:35" id="L678"/> First of all, on the pricing area, pricing, as you know, it depends very much on a particular product line and the competitive situation in the marketplace. <Sync time="01:47:46" id="L679"/> <br/> Nylon -- I think there's a full realization now of the raw material price impact that's been occurring over the last couple of years. <Sync time="01:47:57" id="L680"/> Price announcements by many of the players in this market have already been made, and they are sticking. <Sync time="01:48:04" id="L681"/> <br/> On the second issue with regard to our fluorine capacity, we built two plants. <Sync time="01:48:09" id="L682"/> One of them is primarily focused on refrigerants and the other one is focused on foam-blowing agents. <Sync time="01:48:15" id="L683"/> Both of those plants are up and running very well and we are on track to ramp up the capacity curve. <Sync time="01:48:21" id="L684"/> So we are already achieving significant revenue growth from those investments.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="01:48:27" id="L685"/> We have time for just one more.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="01:48:32" id="L686"/> You know, you look at all of the divestitures this segment has been making over the past 18 months, and you guys are sort of talking about potentially new acquisitions in Spectra and some of these other areas. <Sync time="01:48:45" id="L687"/> I can't help but get a little nervous that several years down the road, we are going to be talking about more divestitures because the returns have become subpar because of the cycle. <Sync time="01:48:53" id="L688"/> Could you talk about, looking forward, what sorts of cost of capital or return criteria you're going to be basing these M&amp;A decisions, including the decision to invest in the new plant that you mentioned, the fluorine plant blending facility in Asia? <Sync time="01:49:06" id="L689"/> Why should we feel better about the portfolio, going forward, and the potential for returns from the portfolio -- apart from cycle wings?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="nancedicciani"><Sync time="01:49:14" id="L690"/> Actually, a couple of reasons. <Sync time="01:49:16" id="L691"/> First of all, the products that we have got in our portfolio and the investments that we have been making are in patented technology areas in high growth areas. <Sync time="01:49:24" id="L692"/> The underlying markets in the areas that we've invested, including these fluorine products, are typically double-digit growth. <Sync time="01:49:32" id="L693"/> <br/> Second of all, with regard to how well we do acquisitions, I think Dave Cote mentioned a new discipline that we put into place within all of Honeywell with regard to strategic matching of criteria, hurdle rates and so forth. <Sync time="01:49:49" id="L694"/> We are not including -- whether it's in my business or any other business -- we're not including sales synergies in our valuations; we are including cost synergies in our valuations. <Sync time="01:50:02" id="L695"/> The hurdle rate is pretty high. <Sync time="01:50:04" id="L696"/> We expect these things to be accretive in the first year, and we are also expect them to return the cost of capital, to stay in the portfolio or to be added to the portfolio. <Sync time="01:50:16" id="L697"/> <br/> So I think, overall, our process is a lot more rigorous and a lot more stringent than it has ever been and I think we are a lot more focused in the areas that we're looking to make investments.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="01:50:28" id="L698"/> Thanks a lot, Nance. <Sync time="01:50:30" id="L699"/> Okay, we're now slated for a 15 minute break. <Sync time="01:50:32" id="L700"/> As you go out there, take a look around. <Sync time="01:50:34" id="L701"/> Tons of products you are hearing about -- propulsion engines, bulletproof vests. <Sync time="01:50:39" id="L702"/> We'll start up promptly at 2:15. <Sync time="01:50:41" id="L703"/> <br/> (Break). <Sync time="01:50:58" id="L704"/> <br/> Okay, we are going to get started again. <Sync time="01:51:18" id="L705"/> If you could, please take your seats. <Sync time="01:52:23" id="L706"/> We will stay on time. <Sync time="01:52:33" id="L707"/> Next up, we have the leader of our Transportation business, Rob Gillette.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="01:53:35" id="L708"/> (Multiple Speakers). <Sync time="01:53:43" id="L709"/> I'll tell you a little bit about our Transportation business. <Sync time="01:54:10" id="L710"/> You've heard quite a bit already about the numbers and the performance, but I want to tell you what we are focusing on and what we see for '04 and what our key priorities are going to be in the business that we are all in. <Sync time="01:56:08" id="L711"/> I'd like you to think I'll leave some time at the end. <Sync time="02:00:32" id="L712"/> We are very interested to hear about your questions when we get to the end of the pinch, so I will try and get through it quickly here. <Sync time="02:05:51" id="L713"/> <br/> Just to review, we talked about Bendix a little bit today; <Sync time="02:05:55" id="L714"/> Dave did in his opening and the fact that Bendix friction materials is now in the portfolio based on the transaction not going through. <Sync time="02:06:05" id="L715"/> So it's friction materials, what we call Turbo Technology, so it's Honeywell Turbo Technologies, that is turbocharging, and our Consumer Products group, which are the brands of FRAM, Prestone, Autolite and Pulse in Europe and Japan. <Sync time="02:06:21" id="L716"/> So that's really what we refer to as TPS in there. <Sync time="02:06:24" id="L717"/> They are all automotive brands and all leaders in their specific segments. <Sync time="02:06:29" id="L718"/> So, they are automotive, but they are pretty different businesses. <Sync time="02:06:32" id="L719"/> I will give you an overview about the businesses and what they are and how they are different, okay? <Sync time="02:06:38" id="L720"/> <br/> Quick, in terms of a review, financially, you can see about half the revenue is turbo, and you can see the balance for friction and CPG in total. 2003 -- Dave to talked you about the financials. <Sync time="02:06:50" id="L721"/> We have the euro in here at 110, so there is some upside in terms of euro conversion. <Sync time="02:06:57" id="L722"/> About approximately you can see half our revenue is in Europe, so what happens with the euro is a big deal to our business because of that. <Sync time="02:07:06" id="L723"/> That's both friction as well as turbochargers. <Sync time="02:07:09" id="L724"/> <br/> You can see the financials there. <Sync time="02:07:12" id="L725"/> I think one point -- if you did the math, that would be about a 15 percent growth in our operating income, so based on the growth and where we are, a large part of that is our turbocharging business but we also plan on recapturing revenue off in the aftermarket in friction. <Sync time="02:07:27" id="L726"/> So that's going to contribute there. <Sync time="02:07:29" id="L727"/> <br/> Our strength overall are the brands that you know about and we talk about all the time leaders really in their industries -- but also the technologies that we have, whether it's turbocharging or friction materials or brake systems. <Sync time="02:07:42" id="L728"/> Gee, you don't have good brands unless you start out with a good product, and we really do have those kinds of things. <Sync time="02:07:48" id="L729"/> <br/> We are global, significantly global, especially in turbocharging. <Sync time="02:07:52" id="L730"/> We also do things on a local basis, whether it's management, sourcing, marketing, that type of thing. <Sync time="02:07:58" id="L731"/> <br/> So that's kind of a brief overview of the business. <Sync time="02:08:01" id="L732"/> We do two things at both times -- growth, which is important -- everybody's talked about it -- and productivity as well. <Sync time="02:08:10" id="L733"/> You know, it's a big focus area for us and has to be. <Sync time="02:08:12" id="L734"/> We don't have the most amiable of customers, as you all know, so they are interested in getting price and us being productive and that type of thing, so we have to do both and we always have. <Sync time="02:08:24" id="L735"/> <br/> Quickly on friction materials, to give you some overview, the businesses are a little bit different. <Sync time="02:08:30" id="L736"/> You can see revenue by channel for friction is about half OE and OE service parts, and the other half is the aftermarket. <Sync time="02:08:39" id="L737"/> S, you will see, when we talk about turbocharging, it's predominantly an OE business; it's technology-based and the way we deliver the product is somewhat different. <Sync time="02:08:48" id="L738"/> In the friction materials business, we do both. <Sync time="02:08:50" id="L739"/> It's pretty global business but significant position in Europe. <Sync time="02:08:54" id="L740"/> The automotive OEs in Europe are still heavily involved in specification of the friction material and the braking systems, so really focused on performance. <Sync time="02:09:03" id="L741"/> So, we do some pretty good business there. <Sync time="02:09:05" id="L742"/> Despite the issues we've had in 2003 with pending transactions and the deal itself, we were able to continue to win new business in the OE market, so we're doing very well there. <Sync time="02:09:18" id="L743"/> Predominance of our business in Europe. <Sync time="02:09:20" id="L744"/> Asia is the focus area for us going into 2004. <Sync time="02:09:23" id="L745"/> We will talk a little bit about that. <Sync time="02:09:25" id="L746"/> Then the Americas is about 27 to 30 percent. <Sync time="02:09:28" id="L747"/> <br/> So, we are the technology leader. <Sync time="02:09:30" id="L748"/> If you hear about a brand called Eurid (ph) in Europe -- it's a very famous brand and one that we position in Europe as a premium product. <Sync time="02:09:38" id="L749"/> So overall, you can see the customers here, OEs in Europe, Tier 1s as we are referred to in the United States, so continental (indiscernible) TRW, people like that we sell to and interact with both in our frictions materials business. <Sync time="02:09:54" id="L750"/> <br/> Dave talked about it earlier in his opening -- I think, you know, 2003 was a tough, tough market condition and tough management job for our team in friction. <Sync time="02:10:04" id="L751"/> You know, when you have a pending transaction in place, it's difficult to keep everybody motivated and focused. <Sync time="02:10:12" id="L752"/> I think he did a great job doing that. <Sync time="02:10:14" id="L753"/> I think, from an overall business standpoint, we mentioned it earlier and Dave Anderson did in his (indiscernible), that we lost aftermarket business. <Sync time="02:10:23" id="L754"/> A lot of our customers in the aftermarket are entrepreneurs (indiscernible) sole proprietorship, so they are 1 million to 2 million in revenue. <Sync time="02:10:32" id="L755"/> They did not view Federal-Mogul as focused as much on the aftermarket as we were, so a lot of them transitioned to other manufacturers to secure their business. <Sync time="02:10:41" id="L756"/> So what we lost quite a bit of business there. <Sync time="02:10:44" id="L757"/> <br/> A big focus area for us is to regain that business in the calendar year of 2004 and really focus on some of the investments that we're putting in place to fund the growth and focus on driving productivity. <Sync time="02:10:57" id="L758"/> So as Dave said, we're really going to focus on the business to maximize the returns. <Sync time="02:11:01" id="L759"/> You can see the financials there going from 3 to 3.5 to close to 6 percent on an operating basis, so not stellar when you measure it against the overall Honeywell but certainly significant improvement year-over-year. <Sync time="02:11:14" id="L760"/> That's really going to be our focus for this year, to grow that side of the business and continue to win with our OE customers. <Sync time="02:11:23" id="L761"/> <br/> On consumer products, you saw some of the things outside here. <Sync time="02:11:26" id="L762"/> We will talk a little bit about the products, the brands and the things we want to work on and focus on in CPG. <Sync time="02:11:33" id="L763"/> You can see, on the left side of this chart is the industry overall and how it's segmented. <Sync time="02:11:38" id="L764"/> Retail, service, (indiscernible) centers OE or OES, so to the OEs themselves and to wholesale distributors, which is what WD stands for. <Sync time="02:11:48" id="L765"/> <br/> On the right side, you can see the segmentation of the business that we have. <Sync time="02:11:52" id="L766"/> So, we are heavy on the retail side and heavy on the branded product sales. <Sync time="02:11:57" id="L767"/> That's how we capture value in CPG and we will talk a little bit about that. <Sync time="02:12:01" id="L768"/> So we want to focus on those pieces of the business and we will continue to. <Sync time="02:12:06" id="L769"/> <br/> Trends in the industry -- everybody knows a lot of the OE manufacturers are trying to give us all these warranty, 100,000 miles all these types of things; they want to keep people like us out from under the hood of the car, right? <Sync time="02:12:19" id="L770"/> So the days of working on your car and changing spark plugs for the DIY market, do-it-yourself market, is a declining segment for that reason. <Sync time="02:12:29" id="L771"/> So you look under the hood of your car today and it's hard to see what you would do to it anyway. <Sync time="02:12:34" id="L772"/> So DIY, which used to be a big deal 20 years ago, is a declining segment for that reason. <Sync time="02:12:40" id="L773"/> <br/> So DIFM, or do-it-for-me, segments have grown, right? <Sync time="02:12:46" id="L774"/> A lot of acronyms, but at least I'm explaining them, right? <Sync time="02:12:49" id="L775"/> It's growing because a lot of people can't do the work themselves, so they put it outside. <Sync time="02:12:55" id="L776"/> <br/> On the industry side, retailers favor branded products. <Sync time="02:12:59" id="L777"/> They favor them because they make more money; it's kind of that easy. <Sync time="02:13:03" id="L778"/> So we invest advertising and the rest to pull those products of off the shelf. <Sync time="02:13:07" id="L779"/> They like to sell our brands because they can make money doing it. <Sync time="02:13:10" id="L780"/> That's where they focus. <Sync time="02:13:12" id="L781"/> <br/> In the overall side, when you get into wholesale distributors and that type of thing, it's the margins aren't there, so we focus on the branded product and the retail side and (inaudible) with what we do. <Sync time="02:13:21" id="L782"/> <br/> So there is a growth bow in appearance products and performance products, which I want to talk a little bit about, because people can't do the heavy-duty do-it-yourself type of work on cars because they don't have the equipment, capability or training to do that, so there is growth in doing the light sides of things like waxes cars and that type of thing, so we distribute some product extensions for Prestone and the car care, whether it's tires, wax, that type of thing. <Sync time="02:13:48" id="L783"/> So we've done a little bit of that. <Sync time="02:13:50" id="L784"/> <br/> We're going to really focus on some new categories, specifically performance, because the performance market is typically a high-margin business and today is a very high growth business. <Sync time="02:14:02" id="L785"/> So a lot of youth buyers want to tune their cars up and are willing to pay quite a bit of money to do that. <Sync time="02:14:07" id="L786"/> We have a product that we are focused on here -- really two in the performance segment. <Sync time="02:14:12" id="L787"/> In FRAWM, it's a brand name, Air Hog, so if you saw that out on the shelf -- many of you may have heard of KNN filters; they are very profitable, high-performance type of market segment. <Sync time="02:14:22" id="L788"/> So it's taking that type of technology and bringing it to our distribution network. <Sync time="02:14:27" id="L789"/> So, a lot of our customers are very excited about this; some see it as an opportunity to extend the brand of product but also to make good money. <Sync time="02:14:34" id="L790"/> So that's one way and you can see the margins there. <Sync time="02:14:38" id="L791"/> <br/> We also even -- believe it or not -- on the market of spark plugs, find technology can drive benefits and we have some new products that we have been able to grow margin with and develop technologies and also serve our customers a little bit better. <Sync time="02:14:52" id="L792"/> In CPG, we're going to focus on the performance segment and differentiate -- continue to differentiate with our brands. <Sync time="02:15:01" id="L793"/> <br/> We have had, for a long time -- and the customers that we sell to today are very interested in our brands, so we focus on winning retailers. <Sync time="02:15:09" id="L794"/> You can see a lot of them up there. <Sync time="02:15:11" id="L795"/> We win because they grow, so we position our products for them, for category managers at Wal-Mart; we do a lot of business with the people you see on this page. <Sync time="02:15:20" id="L796"/> We've been able to grow because we're growing with people who are either expanding horizontally or winning in other ways in the marketplace. <Sync time="02:15:28" id="L797"/> <br/> Onto Turbo Technologies I think. <Sync time="02:15:30" id="L798"/> First is to show you that, in the United States, we don't always see all the things that happen in the world because the products aren't necessarily sold here. <Sync time="02:15:39" id="L799"/> You can see by looking at this picture that we service a lot of new vehicles and provide turbocharging to a lot of new applications that are distributed and sold throughout the world. <Sync time="02:15:51" id="L800"/> You can see some pretty recent models on this slide here. <Sync time="02:15:53" id="L801"/> So, it's not just trucks; it's not just tractors. <Sync time="02:15:57" id="L802"/> It is pass cars. <Sync time="02:15:59" id="L803"/> The predominance of what we do is pass car. <Sync time="02:16:01" id="L804"/> The predominance of that is in Europe. <Sync time="02:16:03" id="L805"/> <br/> I will talk a little bit about the markets and the segmentation and that type of thing. <Sync time="02:16:07" id="L806"/> So really, all of it is the balance of fuel economy, performance and emissions. <Sync time="02:16:12" id="L807"/> None of us want to give up the thrill of driving something that's fun to drive, but they've got to do that in light of hitting an emissions inefficiency. <Sync time="02:16:19" id="L808"/> So that's what this is all about, and how we position our products. <Sync time="02:16:23" id="L809"/> <br/> From a business standpoint, we're still significant in Europe; over 60 percent of our business is in Europe. <Sync time="02:16:29" id="L810"/> You can see North America and Asia in the split. <Sync time="02:16:33" id="L811"/> It is a predominantly OE business, so we work with people who are designing and engineering engines, that want to hit a specific torque curve or power output or whatever it might be. <Sync time="02:16:44" id="L812"/> We design products specifically for them to do and achieve those objectives. <Sync time="02:16:48" id="L813"/> <br/> You can see the revenue growth Dave talked about. <Sync time="02:16:50" id="L814"/> We still are forecasting double-digit revenue growth. <Sync time="02:16:54" id="L815"/> I'll talk a little bit about, by region, what it means to us. <Sync time="02:16:58" id="L816"/> It used to be driven largely by Europe. <Sync time="02:17:00" id="L817"/> Now, with the return of kind of an improvement in the economy in the U.S. and other places, it's improving not only the growth in the economy in Asia but in the United States, now, so I will tell you a little bit about that -- which is great for us because we have the diversity of regions and significant positions in regions around the world, so we can leverage that growth. <Sync time="02:17:22" id="L818"/> <br/> A little bit about our customers and the target -- if look on the left-hand side and kind of look down there, what you see in yellow we kind have dummied down and called 'non-boosted', but this would be something that is not turbocharged. <Sync time="02:17:35" id="L819"/> So, we consider that our market opportunity to pursue, right? <Sync time="02:17:40" id="L820"/> So what you see in color -- all of these customers that you see on the left-hand side here -- you can read what's in red, or what we refer to as boosted or turbocharged engines -- and what is still left in yellow we consider to be our targeted opportunity, going forward. <Sync time="02:17:54" id="L821"/> So remember, all the things that drive this, going forward, you can see on the left side the market of automotive we know is not a growth industry. <Sync time="02:18:04" id="L822"/> I think Roger said earlier, in terms of sensors, it's not that it's an exploding number of unit sales in cars; it's the penetration on those vehicles. <Sync time="02:18:12" id="L823"/> You can see the penetration story there. <Sync time="02:18:14" id="L824"/> So turbocharging is a double-digit growth market worldwide. <Sync time="02:18:19" id="L825"/> Driven by all the things that we've talked about, emissions, economy, performance and people wanting to make products that are fun to drive. <Sync time="02:18:26" id="L826"/> <br/> So overall, you can see we're going to talk a little bit about the split between diesel and gasoline coming up, but diesel has been our past and gasoline will continue to be significant; in the future, diesel will be. <Sync time="02:18:39" id="L827"/> Gasoline is a big part of our future and I will show you why. <Sync time="02:18:45" id="L828"/> <br/> One of the things that drives a lot of the legislation around the world -- or legislation drives our product growth -- is convergence. <Sync time="02:18:53" id="L829"/> You can kind of see it and it doesn't matter what you're measuring, but you know, you can see this is Japan, Europe, the United States. <Sync time="02:19:02" id="L830"/> It's important to note that the boxes you see here are getting closer and closer to each other, right? <Sync time="02:19:07" id="L831"/> So the point is is that, from an external standpoint, emissions requirements are putting a lot of pressure on people to meet and perform to those requirements and they are becoming more and more uniform all over the world, okay? <Sync time="02:19:20" id="L832"/> So this is a big contributor. <Sync time="02:19:22" id="L833"/> <br/> So our customers have to hit these objectives. <Sync time="02:19:25" id="L834"/> You can see the reductions over time. <Sync time="02:19:27" id="L835"/> They've got to do it worldwide, but they've got to do it and make products that we all want to buy. <Sync time="02:19:32" id="L836"/> So their answer to doing a lot of that is turbocharging the engine. <Sync time="02:19:38" id="L837"/> <br/> As kind of an example here, you see diesel on the left, turbocharging on the right. <Sync time="02:19:43" id="L838"/> You can see what the benefits are. <Sync time="02:19:45" id="L839"/> In general, diesel, at equivalent horsepower, will provide anywhere from 30 to 50 percent better fuel economy, right? <Sync time="02:19:54" id="L840"/> So, you get the same driving benefit with significantly better economy, a significant improvement overall. <Sync time="02:20:01" id="L841"/> That's versus a non-turbo gasoline kind of application. <Sync time="02:20:06" id="L842"/> <br/> In gasoline, the value equation is a little bit different. <Sync time="02:20:09" id="L843"/> You can get 10 to 20 percent better economy for the same kind of output, and they do that by downsizing the engine. <Sync time="02:20:15" id="L844"/> So, if you take something that is three today, you make it two liters tomorrow, you turbocharge it, you have a performance that is similar. <Sync time="02:20:23" id="L845"/> So that's kind of the story. <Sync time="02:20:25" id="L846"/> It's in modern cars that you can see all over the world here and it would surprise a lot of people to know that close to 40 percent of all the engines that BMW builds are diesels. <Sync time="02:20:35" id="L847"/> So, living in the United States, you would never know that or recognize that. <Sync time="02:20:39" id="L848"/> <br/> So really, it's all about performance with economy and emissions. <Sync time="02:20:43" id="L849"/> Examples -- our success is driven by diesel penetration in pass cars in Europe. <Sync time="02:20:49" id="L850"/> You can see the numbers and the growth. <Sync time="02:20:52" id="L851"/> Over 40 percent of the market for passenger vehicles in Europe are (sic) diesel. <Sync time="02:20:56" id="L852"/> So depending on what forecast you choose, that's going to continue to happen and growth somewhere between 50 to 60 percent in the next five to seven years, so (inaudible) market penetration of 50 percent or more. <Sync time="02:21:10" id="L853"/> You can see, in Asia, 12 percent in United States won (ph). <Sync time="02:21:16" id="L854"/> So, diesel is an opportunity for the United States in general, specifically as it relates to the vehicles such as light trucks, which we will talk a little bit about in a second. <Sync time="02:21:28" id="L855"/> <br/> All of our growth -- a large part -- has been driven by something we call variable geometry. <Sync time="02:21:34" id="L856"/> We just introduced our latest generation of that variable geometry. <Sync time="02:21:37" id="L857"/> It helps people provide engines that are very drivable, so it makes a diesel engine act more like a gasoline engine. <Sync time="02:21:48" id="L858"/> <br/> Over time and as just kind of a directive chart here, this is the percent of our business that's variable geometry. <Sync time="02:21:56" id="L859"/> You can see out into '05, '06, over 70 percent of the products that we make are variable geometry. <Sync time="02:22:05" id="L860"/> It does a couple of things; it allows our customers to drive a very drivable product; it also allows them to control and hit emissions, so it adds value to them and therefore, it adds value to us. <Sync time="02:22:19" id="L861"/> So it's good news when you see our variable geometry business volume going up; it's good news because it means more margin for us because it's adding more value to our customers. <Sync time="02:22:29" id="L862"/> The fundamental, though, there are a small vanes that we closed down at idle sp that we keep the turbine speed up. <Sync time="02:22:36" id="L863"/> As you build exhaust energy, we open those vanes and let the flow of the exhaust energy drive the turbocharger. <Sync time="02:22:44" id="L864"/> So, in addition to that, it helps us drive the growth that you've seen, so higher average selling price, as well as our margins. <Sync time="02:22:54" id="L865"/> <br/> A little bit on the North American truck segment we were talking at the break -- one of the good things that we have as a business is we're pretty global. <Sync time="02:23:01" id="L866"/> Where we've been suffering a little bit has been the economy in the United States because it's largely driven by business we do in the heavy-duty truck segment, or off-highway segment. <Sync time="02:23:11" id="L867"/> You can see these numbers, I think. 2000 was probably the pinnacle year, maybe pushing 300,000 units. <Sync time="02:23:18" id="L868"/> It's not on this chart -- over time, but you can see the projection for '04 is expected to be well over 200,000 units. <Sync time="02:23:28" id="L869"/> <br/> So, from a business standpoint, that's very good news for all of us, I think. <Sync time="02:23:32" id="L870"/> One is a leading indicator of what people think they are going to haul in 2004, so they are starting to buy (inaudible) goods and services around the United States. <Sync time="02:23:42" id="L871"/> It also says that the market out there has aged and they need to replace those trucks. <Sync time="02:23:47" id="L872"/> So, we are able to drive double-digit growth in North America on markets that we serve for a long period of time. <Sync time="02:23:53" id="L873"/> <br/> The other value side of this is, because they need to hit emissions requirements, more and more of them require variable geometry turbocharges -- so, kind of taken a new value -- the value we've driven in Europe on pass car and applying it commercial diesel. <Sync time="02:24:10" id="L874"/> So, the same story holds -- higher value to them, higher value to us for growth in terms of margin as well. <Sync time="02:24:19" id="L875"/> So that's really the heavy-duty truck segment. <Sync time="02:24:22" id="L876"/> <br/> Another one I'd like to tell you about is light-duty. <Sync time="02:24:25" id="L877"/> So, we make turbochargers for customers who build V-8s that are into what they call a gross vehicle weight over 8,500 pounds in the United States. <Sync time="02:24:37" id="L878"/> That would be like the F-250, the F-350 at Ford, the Silverado 2500, 3500, the diesel vehicles you see. <Sync time="02:24:45" id="L879"/> In that class of vehicles, over 60 percent of those vehicles are diesel today, so it's a growth market and has been -- profit market for our customers, and is also something that is going to continue to grow in the future. <Sync time="02:25:01" id="L880"/> Many of our customers are focused on V-6 engines for the F-150 class of vehicle, so that, we think, is a big growth opportunity for us, going forward. <Sync time="02:25:12" id="L881"/> <br/> Gasoline quickly -- we think, because of the trends we have described, gasoline is going to be a significant growth opportunity in the future. <Sync time="02:25:21" id="L882"/> We want to take some of this technology value that we've created, variable geometry being one of them, and apply that technology and value to gasoline. <Sync time="02:25:29" id="L883"/> So, we're taking the technology development and driving that type of technology into gasoline. <Sync time="02:25:35" id="L884"/> Depending on what you look at, between six to ten million turbocharger opportunity and between 15 to 25 percent growth, or percent of the gasoline engines made. <Sync time="02:25:47" id="L885"/> So same reasons -- emissions, economy, performance. <Sync time="02:25:54" id="L886"/> <br/> Last year and the year before, we talked a little bit about new technologies; we talked about some of the things we do and some of the leverage we can get from Honeywell and other divisions. <Sync time="02:26:05" id="L887"/> I'm just happy to report that we are introducing and providing examples to customers of the E-turbo I told many of you about last year. <Sync time="02:26:12" id="L888"/> So we have an electric motor around this shaft where we can drive the turbocharger in the absence of exhaust flow which, in essence, gives you boost right off idle -- so significant opportunities, sampling customers today. <Sync time="02:26:27" id="L889"/> <br/> We (indiscernible) a little bit from Bob and the Aerospace team with an oil-less turbocharger and we're sampling customers today. <Sync time="02:26:34" id="L890"/> So, it's an air-bearing technology that has Bob has been applying in Aerospace for many, many years, translated it and using it in turbocharging -- a big benefit for our customers, so sampling customers today. <Sync time="02:26:47" id="L891"/> <br/> Dave talked about velocity product development and just quickly, I wanted to say, for us, marketing and growth is all about deciding which target we're going to go after and how we can win. <Sync time="02:26:58" id="L892"/> That's what you see on the left side of this page, that we have marketing people around the world, global accounts all focused and communicating. <Sync time="02:27:04" id="L893"/> We select the right business opportunity, and then we want to introduce those technologies as quickly as possible. <Sync time="02:27:12" id="L894"/> So, for us, that's really leveraging design engineering, assessing and iterating different technologies. <Sync time="02:27:19" id="L895"/> You can see two pieces of software that we are using today is reducing our overall time to introduce new products by 25 percent (sic). <Sync time="02:27:29" id="L896"/> So, by evaluating and doing a lot of testing and assessment electronically before we cut metal, we can introduce products a lot faster, so that helps us grow. <Sync time="02:27:42" id="L897"/> <br/> Just an example, I think, as I think Roger talked a little bit about what they're doing for us with electronics -- we benefit the sensing side of it. <Sync time="02:27:49" id="L898"/> They're working with our team. <Sync time="02:27:51" id="L899"/> We benefit as well from what the guys in Aerospace have done. <Sync time="02:27:54" id="L900"/> You've seen this jet engine out here. <Sync time="02:27:56" id="L901"/> A lot of the things we deal with are similar -- aerodynamics, thermodynamics, all of those types of things. <Sync time="02:28:02" id="L902"/> So, this is really a differentiator for Honeywell and for our turbocharging business is the fact that we have all of these other divisions and that they are able to help and provide the technology and we look at things jointly. <Sync time="02:28:14" id="L903"/> So big, big opportunity for us overall because we're in aerospace and we are in (inaudible) controls and we are leveraging (inaudible). <Sync time="02:28:22" id="L904"/> <br/> A lot of talk about Asia. <Sync time="02:28:23" id="L905"/> I think Nance mentioned, you know, we are building a technology center. <Sync time="02:28:27" id="L906"/> This is a picture of the technology center we're putting in place for our customers in Asia. <Sync time="02:28:33" id="L907"/> We've hired over 80 engineers in the last 16 months in this facility. <Sync time="02:28:39" id="L908"/> You see on the right hand side, we will be burning fuel and testing engines and turbochargers in June of this year, so significant accomplishment by all. <Sync time="02:28:49" id="L909"/> It gives us an opportunity to serve our customers in Asia. <Sync time="02:28:52" id="L910"/> <br/> On the left-hand side, you can see the growth, a lot of opportunity driven by China. <Sync time="02:28:59" id="L911"/> Asia -- in Asia, Korea specifically and Japan, it's the same sales we have in Europe, the technologies that exist -- variable geometry. <Sync time="02:29:07" id="L912"/> We are trying to make to sell and compete in Europe, so it's the higher technology in China. <Sync time="02:29:13" id="L913"/> It's more about providing products and services for China, heavy-duty vehicles and just the growth of the market. <Sync time="02:29:19" id="L914"/> So, we want to have technology capability on the ground and this is our first step in doing that -- and a lot of accomplishment over the year. <Sync time="02:29:29" id="L915"/> <br/> In summary, Turbo Technologies is really about all the things that we talked about but also maintaining our position in leadership of technology, so we invested pretty heavily there; roughly 4 to 5 percent of revenue we invest in engineering development and technology. <Sync time="02:29:44" id="L916"/> We need to really continue to push new technologies to maintain our leadership; that's how we captured value and that's how we will do it in the future. <Sync time="02:29:51" id="L917"/> We really want to continue to leverage all of the technology that Honeywell can bring to bear, whether it's in aerospace, controls or our own organization. <Sync time="02:29:59" id="L918"/> <br/> Consumer products -- think about focusing on the performance market segment and differentiating ourselves by brand extensions and where we can grow. <Sync time="02:30:06" id="L919"/> <br/> Then on friction materials, it's about fixing some of what we couldn't address in 2003, recapturing the aftermarket sales. <Sync time="02:30:16" id="L920"/> Very profitable businesses for us -- and then focusing on the productivity and execution of the business to increase the margin to 5 to 6 percent. <Sync time="02:30:25" id="L921"/> <br/> With that, I will turn it over to Dan for a Q&amp;A.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="02:30:29" id="L922"/> We have time for just a couple. <Sync time="02:30:31" id="L923"/> Let me try to find someone who (indiscernible) a question yet. <Sync time="02:30:35" id="L924"/> Steve McNeil?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="stevemcneil"><Sync time="02:30:40" id="L925"/> Thanks. <Sync time="02:30:41" id="L926"/> Just on the unit shipments in the turbo business, my understanding is there's two turbochargers on the Aserta (ph) engine now. <Sync time="02:30:49" id="L927"/> Does that kind of explain the hockey stick effect here on the unit shipments -- (multiple speakers)?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="02:30:55" id="L928"/> On the heavy-duty market?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="stevemcneil"><Sync time="02:30:56" id="L929"/> Yes.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="02:30:57" id="L930"/> No, that's unit build per vehicles, so what I showed you there is actual Class A (ph) truck shipment plans. <Sync time="02:31:06" id="L931"/> But the two turbos for us -- we supply Caterpillar those turbochargers; that is helping drive the growth in the Americas significantly.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="stevemcneil"><Sync time="02:31:16" id="L932"/> So your growth should be --?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="02:31:17" id="L933"/> At least double-digit in the Americas on the revenue line.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="stevemcneil"><Sync time="02:31:21" id="L934"/> Great. <Sync time="02:31:21" id="L935"/> Can you also just address, philosophically, diesel in U.S.? <Sync time="02:31:25" id="L936"/> I mean, penetration is minuscule. <Sync time="02:31:27" id="L937"/> We seem to think of diesel as these old clunky engines that spew out a lot of (indiscernible).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="02:31:34" id="L938"/> That you don't want to be behind.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="stevemcneil"><Sync time="02:31:35" id="L939"/> Is there just a level of consumer awareness that we need to raise before that business model takes off?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="02:31:44" id="L940"/> Yes.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="stevemcneil"><Sync time="02:31:44" id="L941"/> What's the timeframe for that?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="02:31:46" id="L942"/> I think a couple of things. <Sync time="02:31:48" id="L943"/> I think, why not diesel in the United States in passenger cars, especially (indiscernible)? <Sync time="02:31:53" id="L944"/> We haven't seen too many good ones. <Sync time="02:31:55" id="L945"/> Some of the first forays of General Motors' modified 350 V-8 was a failure, to be honest, that a lot of people have seen in United States. <Sync time="02:32:04" id="L946"/> The second is there's not the driver on the fuel consumption side, so historically -- you know, in Europe, the benefit of buying a liter of diesel versus gasoline is 30 percent less. <Sync time="02:32:20" id="L947"/> Then in addition, you get 30 to 50 percent better fuel economy for the same drivability; it's a big deal. <Sync time="02:32:26" id="L948"/> So that's a legislation in Europe that has driven the growth. <Sync time="02:32:30" id="L949"/> <br/> In the United States, I think there's been no pressure really on fuel economy, so all the guys in Detroit think that big displacement is what sells cars, versus drivability and technology content. <Sync time="02:32:43" id="L950"/> So, there is -- all the European customers are bringing -- for instance, the new SUV from Volkswagen, you have a diesel option. <Sync time="02:32:51" id="L951"/> The E Class Mercedes -- many of you remember the 300 E turbo diesel they are bringing that. <Sync time="02:32:58" id="L952"/> Many of them are just focusing diesel and bringing really good products to market, so we think it's going to happen out of the truck -- high, heavy-duty truck market into the light-duty, so think F-150 Ford, Silverado, General Motors, and a lot of our customs looking at V-6 engines, so smaller engines yet into that class. <Sync time="02:33:19" id="L953"/> So we think it will happen in trucks and we're working with a lot of them to do that. <Sync time="02:33:25" id="L954"/> <br/> One more? <Sync time="02:33:26" id="L955"/> Martin?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="02:33:31" id="L956"/> The unit volume trends that you put up would seem to support a much more aggressive revenue scenario than 10 percent. <Sync time="02:33:42" id="L957"/> What's happening to your costs and I guess the -- and price to drive to that? <Sync time="02:33:56" id="L958"/> In other words, bridge the disconnect?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="robgillette"><Sync time="02:34:03" id="L959"/> I think a lot of the unit's growth volume is coming out of Asia, and so a couple of things -- one is, in Asia, the engines are smaller, the turbochargers are smaller, the average price is lower. <Sync time="02:34:16" id="L960"/> In the United States, you have big engines, big turbochargers, high average price, right? <Sync time="02:34:21" id="L961"/> Dave said we've always been addressing, working with our customers where we have to deal with price pressures every year. <Sync time="02:34:30" id="L962"/> Somewhere between 1 and 2 percent is kind of what we deal with year-over-year, so we drive the productivity as well as the revenue side. <Sync time="02:34:37" id="L963"/> I think, again, remember, we, FX-wise, we are in at 110 (ph) on the euro, so I think it's a reasonable plan for us. <Sync time="02:34:47" id="L964"/> So Europe is a big business overall as well for us, so I guess that would explain a lot of it. <Sync time="02:34:54" id="L965"/> I think when you see the total numbers together for TPS, it includes friction and CPG as well.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="02:35:01" id="L966"/> Thanks a lot, Rob. <Sync time="02:35:01" id="L967"/> The final presentation of the day is by the leader of our Aerospace business, Bob Johnson.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="roberjohnson"><Sync time="02:35:08" id="L968"/> Thank you for staying! <Sync time="02:35:11" id="L969"/> Dave and Dave called me up periodically last year and they would say, is it better yet?! <Sync time="02:35:22" id="L970"/> Settle down, I'm still very conservative. <Sync time="02:35:25" id="L971"/> I want you to know, I did call them late in December and say, "I feel a little bit better." <Sync time="02:35:33" id="L972"/> Because we did start to see some pickup in orders. <Sync time="02:35:36" id="L973"/> We are still working a somewhat-disrupted industry and while flying rates and passengers are up, it's still an industry that's adjusting its capacity and the demand. <Sync time="02:35:52" id="L974"/> We have some issues but it's clear that we saw some change in December. <Sync time="02:35:58" id="L975"/> We still have more work to do. <Sync time="02:35:60" id="L976"/> <br/> What we wanted to do during these last couple of years of the down cycle was put ourselves on important platforms, continue to develop our technology, improve our processes, use these tools and get some of the cash that we have locked up in our business out. <Sync time="02:36:17" id="L977"/> On all of counts, we've made great progress, and we think we are positioned very well for the next couple of years, as the industry does begin to improve. <Sync time="02:36:33" id="L978"/> <br/> What I want to do is walk through the positioning that I've described. <Sync time="02:36:37" id="L979"/> I will talk about it in terms of both the commercial and the defensive space market, and then finally tell you why the underlying processes and ability of the business to deliver there -- and we can deal with some questions at the end <br/> First of all, if I look back a little bit, this is a business that's much more balanced than it used to be. <Sync time="02:36:58" id="L980"/> The defense business before was about 30 percent of our business; it's not 50 percent yet but it's getting closer. <Sync time="02:37:06" id="L981"/> As I said, this capacity in the airlines business is better aligned but there's more work to do. <Sync time="02:37:12" id="L982"/> We still have customers in North America in trouble. <Sync time="02:37:16" id="L983"/> We love regional airlines; we love low-cost carriers. <Sync time="02:37:20" id="L984"/> Asia is in much better shape, and Europe is recovering. <Sync time="02:37:25" id="L985"/> We still have an awful lot of the fleet in North America, the legacy carriers, who have to deal with this yield issue and have begun to work but have more to do to get their unit costs down. <Sync time="02:37:38" id="L986"/> <br/> We see improving what (inaudible) probably 5 percent traffic growth in '04. <Sync time="02:37:43" id="L987"/> We said, last year, that it would be not positive and it ended up being about minus 1, although the fourth quarter was better. <Sync time="02:37:52" id="L988"/> Low-cost carriers are where our target is. <Sync time="02:37:55" id="L989"/> Not only do we sell them products, they like our products, but we also get to do all the service. <Sync time="02:38:01" id="L990"/> We still think that the industry is practicing some constraint and it will be late '05 or '06 before deliveries pick up. <Sync time="02:38:11" id="L991"/> I think that's consistent with what people (inaudible) think. <Sync time="02:38:14" id="L992"/> <br/> From a defense and space standpoint, a real sweet spot. <Sync time="02:38:19" id="L993"/> The new program for defense that the government is focused on and will stay that way requires the technologies that we have. <Sync time="02:38:28" id="L994"/> It also means that the existing fleet can be upgraded, not with necessarily new aircraft but improvements to the existing aircraft, so we are working to get our new products into those older applications, modifications and upgrades. <Sync time="02:38:45" id="L995"/> We have content in space and so the new space program will help. <Sync time="02:38:50" id="L996"/> <br/> I would also say, one of the benefits is that we can move faster than many because of a big content of our business is commercially priced and commercial practices. <Sync time="02:39:01" id="L997"/> <br/> The industry still has to deal with this cyclical nature of the airline business. <Sync time="02:39:07" id="L998"/> I think the defense focus is going to be consistent for a period of time. <Sync time="02:39:12" id="L999"/> Long OEM production runs keep us in a good place. <Sync time="02:39:17" id="L1000"/> What we have experienced and continue to experience, both in military and commercial, is that successful customers don't want to do all the work themselves, and so it puts us in a decision point where the work is decided; also, it takes advantage of our improved reliability. <Sync time="02:39:35" id="L1001"/> So, the -- (technical difficulty) -- of the industry are still sound and we think we're well positioned. <Sync time="02:39:42" id="L1002"/> <br/> Why are we successful? <Sync time="02:39:43" id="L1003"/> A whole long list -- I won't read them but I think technology is at the top, being on almost everything -- in fact everything that flies and now things that are on the ground is well. <Sync time="02:39:55" id="L1004"/> I think our relationship with our customer helps us take bigger and more complete solutions to our customers. <Sync time="02:40:02" id="L1005"/> We have great people; <Sync time="02:40:04" id="L1006"/> I will show you some win rates and backlog charts that are incredible. <Sync time="02:40:10" id="L1007"/> If anything, as we've studied how to grow better, we've learned to be more selective around what we sign up to grow in, both in terms of products and applications so that we are hitting sweet spots, which may not be every spot. <Sync time="02:40:25" id="L1008"/> We have a history of executing and we actually think we've gotten better, so as the industry gets better, we will get better. <Sync time="02:40:35" id="L1009"/> <br/> The strategies -- and I mentioned these last year -- are the same and they've been the same for three years. <Sync time="02:40:41" id="L1010"/> Don't just get on new platforms, but take these better products into the aftermarket and the existing fleet. <Sync time="02:40:48" id="L1011"/> We're doing that and I will show you places where we've been successful -- integrate systems so we can have smarter airplanes, extend the services because our customers don't want to do that as much as they used to, help make the planes safe. <Sync time="02:41:02" id="L1012"/> You've probably seen some of the ads about auto recovery, so there are ways that we can take our technology and add more value to the owner. <Sync time="02:41:12" id="L1013"/> <br/> Then some great work we've done to make these planes smarter, so that not only can we fix them when they break but we can help the customer understand how to have less waste of inventory so that we are able to predict the failures that have been done in other industries. <Sync time="02:41:29" id="L1014"/> <br/> So we are in a place where many of our competitors aren't at a time when the industry is recovering. <Sync time="02:41:36" id="L1015"/> <br/> Comparisons -- the revenue will be up slightly. <Sync time="02:41:41" id="L1016"/> Operating margins (indiscernible) Dave talked about -- both Daves talked about the fact we have some IP licensing that will be less this year. <Sync time="02:41:52" id="L1017"/> We also are investing in technology. <Sync time="02:41:55" id="L1018"/> I would remind us that fuel costs are up, yields are down, and so while our customers have started to buy when they had to, it will take them -- first of all, they are not going to reach back and buy the inventory that they've learned to live without. <Sync time="02:42:10" id="L1019"/> It will be a little bit longer before I think they release all their purchasing efforts to buy products. <Sync time="02:42:17" id="L1020"/> So I think, at the time, (inaudible) should be a little more conservative about what people's reactions and things getting better is. <Sync time="02:42:25" id="L1021"/> I think there will be a small lag here. <Sync time="02:42:27" id="L1022"/> <br/> Our business is balanced between the mechanical and the electronic. <Sync time="02:42:31" id="L1023"/> It's also much more balanced between commercial and defense. <Sync time="02:42:35" id="L1024"/> On the strengths, I put the people first. <Sync time="02:42:38" id="L1025"/> These are very smart people who work in a complex industry, and I think their real benefit is how well they work together. <Sync time="02:42:46" id="L1026"/> As we improve the underlying processes, we make it easier for them to work together. <Sync time="02:42:51" id="L1027"/> Again, it takes big solutions to customers. <Sync time="02:42:54" id="L1028"/> <br/> We talked about this IT action and I have a chart there. <Sync time="02:42:58" id="L1029"/> We found, when we started to put in these common systems, that we actually had 1,924 different software and program applications. <Sync time="02:43:08" id="L1030"/> Much is the result of all the companies that were in our heritage, so we're making some progress on it. <Sync time="02:43:15" id="L1031"/> I think that gives us great efficiency in the future. <Sync time="02:43:19" id="L1032"/> <br/> Being close to the customers -- and I'll show you some charts here where we've made significant headway in reducing our working capital as part of a great cash program. <Sync time="02:43:32" id="L1033"/> <br/> If I divide this market up in all of its different places -- because we play in every market -- first, between both the aftermarket and the OEM and then between business jets, regional, air transport and then defense and space -- a bigger spread here you can see. <Sync time="02:43:50" id="L1034"/> I've also tried to highlight where these changes are. <Sync time="02:43:54" id="L1035"/> We think the business and general aviation aftermarket will pick up a bit in flying hours. <Sync time="02:43:59" id="L1036"/> We are also dealing with more efficient and reliable products, so a bit of a lag. <Sync time="02:44:06" id="L1037"/> In the business jets, we see the production stabilizing, so we're not on the downswing any more. <Sync time="02:44:12" id="L1038"/> It's slightly positive to that because we have more penetration in terms of (indiscernible) and our new propulsion engine . <Sync time="02:44:20" id="L1039"/> <br/> The regional aftermarket off a little bit -- while that market, in fact, is flying more because we have had in the aftermarket some of the retirement of the original (inaudible) engines, which are now being replaced. <Sync time="02:44:33" id="L1040"/> <br/> The regional OEM certainly is growing 18 percent but our content is because of the epic introduction into almost every application. <Sync time="02:44:43" id="L1041"/> <br/> Air transport improved, in the aftermarket, about consistent with the rate of utilization. <Sync time="02:44:51" id="L1042"/> The air transport OEM just about flat -- we have a little content benefit. <Sync time="02:44:58" id="L1043"/> <br/> Defense and space aftermarket up 5 percent, which is about the rate of utilization we see. <Sync time="02:45:05" id="L1044"/> OEM, while the defense production is up and we have some ending development programs on the LB-100 which, while low margin, (indiscernible) the benefit of the sale. <Sync time="02:45:17" id="L1045"/> So kind of a big spread of mix but it comes out to the positive side. <Sync time="02:45:24" id="L1046"/> <br/> While we have gone through this cycle, we have continued to invest in programs. <Sync time="02:45:29" id="L1047"/> On the left side, you can see that it's still a very significant investment and the Company-funded piece of this is consistent. <Sync time="02:45:38" id="L1048"/> As we've dropped off on some of the completions of our programs, some of the customer-funded pieces dropped. <Sync time="02:45:45" id="L1049"/> I show you here that we are on the declining side of the new engine investment in the HTF 7000, the former AS 900. <Sync time="02:45:56" id="L1050"/> We are also past the high point on Primus Epic, but as you can see, there a number of other programs there in different technologies that are tied to our strategies, which are on the increase. <Sync time="02:46:09" id="L1051"/> So, we are constantly remixing that as we advance through our strategies. <Sync time="02:46:14" id="L1052"/> But you can see it's across the board in all the different parts of our business. <Sync time="02:46:21" id="L1053"/> <br/> Winning has been fun! <Sync time="02:46:24" id="L1054"/> This is quite a story, and this is through the economic cycle. <Sync time="02:46:28" id="L1055"/> Last year, we had about $9 billion of wins pretty well balanced between commercial and defense, and 52 billion over the last five years, which has been a rather interesting five years. <Sync time="02:46:43" id="L1056"/> So, we continue to win, and our win rate is very high at 83 percent. <Sync time="02:46:48" id="L1057"/> I think that says we're getting the right technologies to the right platforms, even at a time when we're being more selective and investing in new technologies. <Sync time="02:47:00" id="L1058"/> <br/> I drill down into it -- I'm not going to read the chart, but I think this is one of the strengths because we are across the complete spectrum. <Sync time="02:47:10" id="L1059"/> Some of these and even more are what I would call the second and third tier, where we make components for people who make engines who make engines for airplanes. <Sync time="02:47:22" id="L1060"/> We're also making smarter components, along with smarter individual LRUs (ph) here. <Sync time="02:47:31" id="L1061"/> <br/> If I sort that commercial market out between different types of platforms -- the arrows indicate whether they are increasing, or in the case of regional turboprops, declining, or staying relatively flat, as in general aviation. <Sync time="02:47:47" id="L1062"/> You can see our content per ship set. <Sync time="02:47:49" id="L1063"/> You can also see our aftermarket (indiscernible) annual aircraft utilization in (indiscernible). <Sync time="02:47:57" id="L1064"/> It really indicates that our content on platforms that are increasing is increasing, which also carries with it a higher longer-term aftermarket content. <Sync time="02:48:08" id="L1065"/> So I think we are in some very good places with the right technology. <Sync time="02:48:14" id="L1066"/> <br/> If I come back and tie those five high-level strategies against examples of where we have invested and where those are growth opportunities, you can see the Primus Epic; you can see here Smart Valves, for example, modular aircraft controls, high-technology repairs. <Sync time="02:48:33" id="L1067"/> So, we're going into the places where we think our customers and markets need to go to help them be successful. <Sync time="02:48:42" id="L1068"/> <br/> We have continued to be an innovation company. <Sync time="02:48:45" id="L1069"/> A real (inaudible) here is our ability to invent those technologies and through the years, we have done that on both the mechanical and electronic side of our business. <Sync time="02:48:56" id="L1070"/> Here, currently, 2000 and beyond, you can see that we are working on integrated systems -- AS (ph), Primus Epic -- tools that help our customers fly smarter and more successful in their missions. <Sync time="02:49:14" id="L1071"/> <br/> We have former AS 900, the new Honeywell Turbofan 7000, and the Blue (ph) had its successful launch this year. <Sync time="02:49:24" id="L1072"/> What Bombardier described as its greatest and easiest entry into service is now having conversations with other aircraft manufacturers, based upon the success of that aircraft, its ease-of-use and entry into service for other applications. <Sync time="02:49:42" id="L1073"/> You see here some key (inaudible) on the number of installed base, so we think we have a great application that needs to find more applications, so I think this is the time that we will start to find those. <Sync time="02:49:54" id="L1074"/> Lots of improvements in its technology and application, which are very attractive to people making the next set of business jets. <Sync time="02:50:05" id="L1075"/> <br/> We talked before in prior years about not having enough content on Airbus, and in several years, we started that. <Sync time="02:50:14" id="L1076"/> I remember, back in 1997-98 time period, I met with Airbus and they said, "Look, here's what you have to do. <Sync time="02:50:23" id="L1077"/> You have to become a preferred supplier, not just to us but to our customers." <Sync time="02:50:29" id="L1078"/> So, we worked on fill rates and quality and reliability and in many cases moved from what was the bottom of their supply rating system to the top. <Sync time="02:50:39" id="L1079"/> Then in the A380 competition, that turned into wins. <Sync time="02:50:43" id="L1080"/> Ten wins across the board in different set of technology -- and what it does, over time, as that aircraft enters service and becomes a bigger part of the fleet, it means we are a bigger part of the fleet. <Sync time="02:50:57" id="L1081"/> It also puts us in a position to become the next aircraft that they make new model applications (sic). <Sync time="02:51:08" id="L1082"/> <br/> I make a comparison here between our content on various Boeing aircraft and the Airbus aircraft, and you can see that, while not the same in the past, we have leveled this field -- I think important at a time when Airbus has established themselves as an equal player in this market. <Sync time="02:51:33" id="L1083"/> So, we have more content at a time when they are selling more. <Sync time="02:51:39" id="L1084"/> <br/> The Primus Epic has a number of certifications, and this year, we will have even more. <Sync time="02:51:46" id="L1085"/> You can see the number of installed base in the short-term here, the amount of revenue that it generates. <Sync time="02:51:54" id="L1086"/> It is highly successful and it has become a differentiator; in other words, it's one of the reasons that aircraft OEM makers are using to sell differentiate their product (sic), and there are all slightly different versions of Primus Epic that have been adapted to their needs. <Sync time="02:52:11" id="L1087"/> It has also enabled, in some cases, the aircraft manufacturer to put more seats on a plane or to add other features or to make the cabin roomier, because the system takes out weight and size requirements and gives the manufacturer more opportunities. <Sync time="02:52:32" id="L1088"/> <br/> One of the areas that has grown significantly in double digits last year is our service business. <Sync time="02:52:39" id="L1089"/> What we wanted to do is move up the food chain and take advantage as well on maintenance service agreements of increased reliability in our products. <Sync time="02:52:49" id="L1090"/> Without exception, the new low-cost carriers have selected our products and also signed up for our maintenance. <Sync time="02:52:58" id="L1091"/> That puts us in a decision process. <Sync time="02:53:01" id="L1092"/> <br/> Also, a number of the Legacy carriers have also started to take a look at how they invest their own money and then started to increase their rate of outsourcing. <Sync time="02:53:12" id="L1093"/> That puts us not just in a higher order of decision process on the spare parts, it also gives us the volume (inaudible) and the support work. <Sync time="02:53:24" id="L1094"/> <br/> We are also in the business of customizing service offerings, moving up into logistics and understanding and becoming a part of the inventory system of our customers. <Sync time="02:53:36" id="L1095"/> Here you can see that airlines are increasing the amount of outsourcing they do in total, and a big piece of that in total. <Sync time="02:53:44" id="L1096"/> They are also moving the work of the aircraft maintenance out to service integrators, which moves us up into a preferred space. <Sync time="02:53:53" id="L1097"/> It also puts us in a place to introduce, more simply on our own, the modifications and upgrades from our supplier partnerships and be able to be more predictive than our supply chain which helps not only us and our customers but the supply chain be more efficient so we be more predictive about the work that's required. <Sync time="02:54:16" id="L1098"/> <br/> We talked before about some of the things we want on the A380. <Sync time="02:54:20" id="L1099"/> One example of this is the technology integration of what we call the environmental surveillance system, AESS. <Sync time="02:54:28" id="L1100"/> But it's (indiscernible) was on the upper left here, a whole bunch of systems that both weighed and had complexity, also had service and technical support requirements and integrated into a much simpler system from a cost and weight standpoint but at the same time gives the pilot one integrated safety message, not at times three or four. <Sync time="02:54:54" id="L1101"/> So the pilots love it; the aircraft owners and manufacturers like it as well. <Sync time="02:55:02" id="L1102"/> <br/> We talked about one of the acquisitions we made was Chadwick (indiscernible). <Sync time="02:55:08" id="L1103"/> What we started out applying it to was engines so that we could be more predictive about -- based on temperature or vibration and (indiscernible) -- what the state of the engine was in terms of when the repair was going to be required. <Sync time="02:55:25" id="L1104"/> We've done that both on commercial and military. <Sync time="02:55:28" id="L1105"/> We are moving it up so that it applies more to engines throughout the system of the aircraft, across the system, back down into the service and support operation of the owner -- and then to get all the way out and tie to the logistics tail so that we are helping our customers, both in the military case and commercial, understand the status of their equipment so they can help get the inventory out. <Sync time="02:55:53" id="L1106"/> It's a big winner and I'll show you some charts, especially on the military, (inaudible) that's started out even faster. <Sync time="02:56:01" id="L1107"/> <br/> If I get to the end of this commercial story, you can see here I'm trying to reach out and give you a sense that we are past the bottom. <Sync time="02:56:09" id="L1108"/> The blue bars are what we think are realistic commercial OEM deliveries, so we are past the bottom and it's clearly on the upside. <Sync time="02:56:19" id="L1109"/> We can talk about at what rate the airlines start improving their purchases, but I think, from a conservative standpoint, it's clear in sometime late in '05 or '06 that will happen. (indiscernible) our growth or in some cases here a decline in the green has clearly past the bottom. <Sync time="02:56:40" id="L1110"/> We almost got back to 0 here in '03, and we are predicting, again, a 5 percent improvement in '04. <Sync time="02:56:48" id="L1111"/> <br/> I think we have the right technologies for the right customers; we are on great platforms that are going to be a part of this growth, so one of our goals here was to be well positioned for the economic turn, and we think we are. <Sync time="02:57:04" id="L1112"/> <br/> If I go to defense and space, you know, many people think that we are in the aircraft business and that's true, but we are also in the space business, the ground vehicle business, and precision strike, as was exhibited in many of the conflicts in the Middle East. (indiscernible) have not experienced it myself but we can hit a doorknob from 25,000 feet from 25 miles. <Sync time="02:57:32" id="L1113"/> I can't tell you much more than that because we shouldn't know much more than specifically but that's pretty precise. <Sync time="02:57:40" id="L1114"/> I think, as we watch the conflicts in the Middle East, we saw that accuracy. <Sync time="02:57:47" id="L1115"/> <br/> The Defense and Space I divided up just give you a sense of all of the products that we have on these applications -- the aircraft and the vehicles on the left, the missiles in the middle and then, as President Bush has emphasized, a new focus for NASA and the space industry -- lots of products from the cockpit and the avionics to the mechanical parts, so that across the board here in all these areas, we have lots of content and lots of technology. <Sync time="02:58:21" id="L1116"/> <br/> If I look at the requirements here in the dark blue, we have to continue to fight the War on Terror. <Sync time="02:58:28" id="L1117"/> We have transformation so that the Armed Forces can fight from a distance with less loss of life and greater accuracy. <Sync time="02:58:36" id="L1118"/> We also have an international expansion so that we can get things to places internationally in great speeds. <Sync time="02:58:44" id="L1119"/> The implications of that are in the middle, and the little arrows indicate our content and the direction it is taking. <Sync time="02:58:52" id="L1120"/> Defense spending is up, which is a positive to us; <Sync time="02:58:55" id="L1121"/> Homeland Security initiatives, in the near-term, we've seen some real emphasis and some decisions which will be favorable to us. <Sync time="02:59:03" id="L1122"/> This (indiscernible)-centric warfare -- and I'll show you later that it's both electronic (indiscernible) and mechanical components, both in the air and on land, all bode very favorably to us. <Sync time="02:59:17" id="L1123"/> We are making things that last longer. <Sync time="02:59:20" id="L1124"/> We are also helping the Armed Services do less of this maintenance and spend less money on people, more on the technology, as we become the person they outsource this to. <Sync time="02:59:32" id="L1125"/> <br/> We have a number of international opportunities I will describe to you. <Sync time="02:59:36" id="L1126"/> This ability to take the older fleets and put new technology on them, including old bombs and bigger bullets with greater guidance materials -- very significant. <Sync time="02:59:48" id="L1127"/> So all of those fit into what our growth priorities are, and so we have, we think, not only a growing category but it will continue to be a higher percentage of our share and of our sales. <Sync time="03:00:02" id="L1128"/> <br/> If I drill that down on the left, our Secretary Rumsfeld's priorities, and then I tried to describe them in some shading here between what was core, what was transformational and what is embryonic. <Sync time="03:00:18" id="L1129"/> So you see that we go from the retrofit (indiscernible) to aftermarket support across to precision strike in the Homeland Security and then eventually, this whole new set of warfare tools. <Sync time="03:00:31" id="L1130"/> In there, you'll see below that, what that means to us. <Sync time="03:00:35" id="L1131"/> It means, for example, in retrofits, we can upgrade fleets; we are working with our customer to do that, and to be the implementer of some of those changes. <Sync time="03:00:45" id="L1132"/> You can see, on precision strike, that all this means they need more accuracy on more devices; we're doing that. <Sync time="03:00:53" id="L1133"/> <br/> A new platform -- I'll show you the breadth of the technology that we are applying. <Sync time="03:00:58" id="L1134"/> So across the board, where this is going we believe is sustainable and gives us more and more opportunities. <Sync time="03:01:05" id="L1135"/> The good news is it's not as constrained because we're using commercial practices and some of the products we've developed for commercial purposes. <Sync time="03:01:16" id="L1136"/> <br/> If I drill that down even further, you can see those same blocks. <Sync time="03:01:20" id="L1137"/> I'm giving you specific applications of aircraft and opportunities here. <Sync time="03:01:26" id="L1138"/> I would say that I think the future and some of the border security will come from not just unmanned vehicles but organic vehicles that are remote-controlled, so that we can see and are more protected using higher technology from a distance that reports back. <Sync time="03:01:46" id="L1139"/> I think the emphasis here is the processing of information and how quickly decisions can be made using new sets of technology that don't require as much human intervention. <Sync time="03:01:58" id="L1140"/> Great opportunities and I have described down at the bottom the growth potential in a relatively short period of time. <Sync time="03:02:09" id="L1141"/> <br/> (indiscernible) look at this whole network-centric warfare, you can see some of this is about modifying some of the applications, developing new technology and then filling gaps. <Sync time="03:02:20" id="L1142"/> I would suggest all of those mean that there's a greater set of technology and integration in use and transmission of information in making decision. <Sync time="03:02:31" id="L1143"/> It's not just in the air; it's in the air; it's on the ground; it's in different marine applications. <Sync time="03:02:38" id="L1144"/> In the little picture up here is one of those new surveillance vehicles that will have lots of content, both from propulsion, a guidance and a communications standpoint, so we are extremely well positioned for those. <Sync time="03:02:54" id="L1145"/> Again, we've started some of the opportunities to win. <Sync time="03:02:58" id="L1146"/> <br/> Here I show you this future combat system -- $1 million per ship set. <Sync time="03:03:02" id="L1147"/> You can see that we have won a number of products here, some of them more electronic, but we're also a part of the logistics decisions support process. <Sync time="03:03:14" id="L1148"/> On the right are decisions still to be made with lots of opportunity for our products and it excites us. <Sync time="03:03:22" id="L1149"/> We are in the middle of a competition about what the propulsion for this is. <Sync time="03:03:27" id="L1150"/> I think we've made some headway to say, from a marketing standpoint, that diesels may cost less but over the life and use of the vehicle, our propulsion engine does a lot more and costs a lot less if you look at the use and application. <Sync time="03:03:44" id="L1151"/> I think there are a number of people listening to those advantages. <Sync time="03:03:51" id="L1152"/> <br/> We talked before about the joint strike fighter. <Sync time="03:03:55" id="L1153"/> Here you can see the number of aircraft, the value per ship set in the total application -- a whole number and spread of our applications on here. <Sync time="03:04:05" id="L1154"/> This is one of the places we were most successful in selling the value and the weight reduction of having an integrated set of products in a system. <Sync time="03:04:14" id="L1155"/> That program is well on schedule and well within the targets that we set for it. <Sync time="03:04:21" id="L1156"/> I am going to talk to Lockheed Martin about it. <Sync time="03:04:23" id="L1157"/> They say they don't have a better supplier in terms of what we committed and what we are delivering. <Sync time="03:04:29" id="L1158"/> <br/> From an international standpoint, the A400-M is the military version or application from the A380. <Sync time="03:04:38" id="L1159"/> A number of those products that we have embedded in that will be the same products selected on the A400. (inaudible) lots of potential on that aircraft. <Sync time="03:04:48" id="L1160"/> <br/> As well, in Japan, the CXPX (ph) has a number of our applications. <Sync time="03:04:56" id="L1161"/> We are very confident about that, and that's an application that we are positive about. <Sync time="03:05:02" id="L1162"/> I had a minute when I was in Japan this year to speak to the Chief of the Air Force of Japan, who probably had a lot of things to do. <Sync time="03:05:10" id="L1163"/> We spent 45 minutes talking about the history of Honeywell and the Honeywell Company supporting them. <Sync time="03:05:18" id="L1164"/> He was very appreciative and I asked him, does he have any issues with any of our products. <Sync time="03:05:23" id="L1165"/> Now, this is a vastly (inaudible) lots of products and he said he had none. <Sync time="03:05:27" id="L1166"/> I'm sure he asked ahead of time. <Sync time="03:05:29" id="L1167"/> So, good business and I think it leads to these next set of selections on the cargo aircraft. <Sync time="03:05:38" id="L1168"/> <br/> Future applications -- President Bush talked about a new emphasis and direction for NASA. <Sync time="03:05:44" id="L1169"/> We've really come to the end of that initial business; it's time to set another one. <Sync time="03:05:49" id="L1170"/> I point out here that on the existing space shuttle ship set, we have about $50 million of content; on the international space, we have a significant amount of content as well. <Sync time="03:06:01" id="L1171"/> Now, there aren't a lot of these units but there are going to be some units, so we think we're very well positioned to continue to be a partner with the Space Program. <Sync time="03:06:15" id="L1172"/> <br/> Precision-guided munitions I spoke of earlier; this has the potential to be a $4 billion business over the next ten years. <Sync time="03:06:24" id="L1173"/> I tried to project that out. <Sync time="03:06:27" id="L1174"/> This is not just about replacing the units that have been consumed; it's also about upgrading the units that are in storage; it's also about moving down into different forms of projectiles, what I like to call big bullets -- not little bullets but at least big bullets, which gets from the big things that we drive from aircraft. <Sync time="03:06:49" id="L1175"/> So very important that the accuracy of these be there, and so they are using what we call our MIMS (ph) technology to do that -- much more accurate, weighs less. <Sync time="03:07:01" id="L1176"/> <br/> I think Dave had a meeting with some of the people -- chiefs of the Air Force recently. <Sync time="03:07:06" id="L1177"/> The talked about how significant it is, how important it is and how accurate it is. <Sync time="03:07:12" id="L1178"/> While we have a wonderful history, we also understand how important it is to maintain that. <Sync time="03:07:18" id="L1179"/> <br/> Aftermarket services I mentioned, and this is in the defense area -- not dissimilar from our commercial experience but here's $1.9 billion of wins and they are on specific platforms, helicopter platforms, Navy logistics platforms, defense Logistics Agency. <Sync time="03:07:37" id="L1180"/> So, as the government wants its dollars to work more effectively, it is choosing to do less, rely upon its suppliers more and it puts us in the decision process. <Sync time="03:07:48" id="L1181"/> As you can see, we've only begun. <Sync time="03:07:50" id="L1182"/> So, I think our ability to predict, have the parts there just in time -- and you will see later, I want to emphasize our own ability to do that without having as much inventory so that we are a part of making the whole supply chain more efficient. <Sync time="03:08:06" id="L1183"/> <br/> To summarize this defense, I believe and I think the record shows that we have great technology in a great place. <Sync time="03:08:14" id="L1184"/> We foresaw the changes that were going to happen in the defense strategies and related them to our technology. <Sync time="03:08:21" id="L1185"/> We've had a wonderful history of winning and it is a much more and will continue to be a much more significant part of our business. <Sync time="03:08:30" id="L1186"/> <br/> But we're still not as good as we ought to be. <Sync time="03:08:35" id="L1187"/> We used to have terrible working capital turns; it has improved slightly. <Sync time="03:08:43" id="L1188"/> The working capital turns are here -- this year, plan to be up to 4.5 -- a long way from 9 but it's going the right direction. <Sync time="03:08:53" id="L1189"/> Part of that is Accounts Payable; part of that is in inventory, but actually, at the same time, we are improving our deliveries. <Sync time="03:09:02" id="L1190"/> So, as Roger said, this distance between ourselves and the customers has lessened. <Sync time="03:09:07" id="L1191"/> That means we're working more efficiently but we've made great improvement and we're getting the cash lock-up out of these hiding places. <Sync time="03:09:17" id="L1192"/> <br/> We're doing that what the right tools. <Sync time="03:09:19" id="L1193"/> We have and will continue to benefit from all the training we've done, both in Black Stealth (ph) design for Six Sigma and Greenbelt (indiscernible) and I have my certification! <Sync time="03:09:34" id="L1194"/> I plight is to some intellectual property things that helped us this last year. <Sync time="03:09:39" id="L1195"/> But we have more to do. <Sync time="03:09:41" id="L1196"/> I think we've only just touched the tip of the iceberg here around the benefits because it has become a culture. <Sync time="03:09:48" id="L1197"/> I speak to our suppliers; <Sync time="03:09:50" id="L1198"/> I speak to our customers and they've learned with us and they know they can count on us to go solve a problem the right way, using data and changing the process. <Sync time="03:09:60" id="L1199"/> So it has worked. <Sync time="03:10:01" id="L1200"/> We have more training to do but I think the bulk of the training is behind us. <Sync time="03:10:08" id="L1201"/> <br/> We talk about velocity product development. <Sync time="03:10:09" id="L1202"/> While I think we get great products to market, I think that the world is going to go faster, so we want to get these to market faster. <Sync time="03:10:18" id="L1203"/> I think velocity also says to do it right the first time. <Sync time="03:10:22" id="L1204"/> We've had some experience of doing these things multiple times, and it's a lot less stressful to get them done faster the first time. <Sync time="03:10:31" id="L1205"/> Some of this goes back to working with the customers right at the beginning to understand the specifications, build them into the safety queues (ph) and do the job once. <Sync time="03:10:41" id="L1206"/> <br/> I'm always amazed sometimes when we are so able to fix these things that might happen sporadically. <Sync time="03:10:49" id="L1207"/> It tells me we've got a lot of resources sitting around to fixed things. <Sync time="03:10:52" id="L1208"/> Why didn't we apply them to more growth opportunities in the first place? <Sync time="03:10:56" id="L1209"/> <br/> As you can see here, we have some targets that are not exactly doing things with 50 percent of the time expended but pretty close. <Sync time="03:11:05" id="L1210"/> They are in every area of our development and in each part of the business, and they are using new tools. <Sync time="03:11:11" id="L1211"/> Many of the Six Sigma and lean tools apply to the area of product development. <Sync time="03:11:19" id="L1212"/> <br/> Cycle time reduction -- you can see here the reduction in POS and we're also applying this to cold starts and warmth starts. <Sync time="03:11:27" id="L1213"/> It's deployed down the organization into the metrics, a lot of time using these tools and it becomes a way of life. <Sync time="03:11:35" id="L1214"/> I don't know that we've done a great job of improving our voice to the customer (indiscernible). <Sync time="03:11:41" id="L1215"/> It's almost amazing. <Sync time="03:11:42" id="L1216"/> People have copied and modeled our process but I think, as we have to reduce inventory, it means we have to deliver the products to the customers with the same efficiency but without the time to have the inventory covering it. <Sync time="03:11:56" id="L1217"/> So if we take the inventory down, we have to get better and faster at what we do. <Sync time="03:12:01" id="L1218"/> We've made some headway. <Sync time="03:12:03" id="L1219"/> It's built into my goals and objectives and there are no employees in our Aerospace company that don't have this built into their objectives and the tools they're going to use and how they are going to get it done. <Sync time="03:12:16" id="L1220"/> We are keeping score, and when we keep score, we get things done. <Sync time="03:12:22" id="L1221"/> <br/> Quality and delivery is a part of that. <Sync time="03:12:24" id="L1222"/> Our Sigma here in 2002 was 4. <Sync time="03:12:28" id="L1223"/> We've made, from a Sigma standpoint, some great progress. <Sync time="03:12:32" id="L1224"/> But it also says we've a long way to go, and I think that's tied to this whole ability to deliver to the customers' requests or ahead of time. <Sync time="03:12:42" id="L1225"/> So, it's ability to have everything in our business moving a little bit faster. <Sync time="03:12:46" id="L1226"/> We have actions deployed, then, by site (ph); they are in each person; they are tied to compensation. <Sync time="03:12:52" id="L1227"/> We also have councils where we show different sites the best practices of other sites, so we make this contagious process of change. <Sync time="03:13:03" id="L1228"/> <br/> We talked about information technology -- 1,924 different systems. <Sync time="03:13:09" id="L1229"/> We've worked with Bearing Point and SAP. <Sync time="03:13:11" id="L1230"/> We've taken people from other parts of the Company that have deployed this and embedded them in our process that we have best practices. <Sync time="03:13:20" id="L1231"/> We also work with Bearing Point. <Sync time="03:13:21" id="L1232"/> We have, across our whole Aerospace business, 95 percent commonality in the systems, which I think is the failure mode of having a common system is not to make them common and in this case, we have. <Sync time="03:13:33" id="L1233"/> What they will do is they will enable us to have common functional disciplines and to do that with fewer resources. <Sync time="03:13:40" id="L1234"/> <br/> We are making a big investment; we started last year. <Sync time="03:13:44" id="L1235"/> We have a big set of things across all of the sites to do this year. <Sync time="03:13:49" id="L1236"/> It goes a bit down next year, and then we will start getting some of the benefits of this in '05. <Sync time="03:13:55" id="L1237"/> We have gone live in some of our service businesses and it frees up great amounts of resources and makes us more efficient. <Sync time="03:14:04" id="L1238"/> <br/> Dave talked about marketing and I told you this one case on (indiscernible) on the future combat system where I think we changed our approach to selling the product line; <Sync time="03:14:16" id="L1239"/> I know we did. <Sync time="03:14:17" id="L1240"/> I think we also understood how to help the customer improve his total view of what the value of the product and the whole life cycle was (inaudible) part of understanding how to make solutions and sell the way our customer buys and where the value is. <Sync time="03:14:36" id="L1241"/> So, that's made a big difference. <Sync time="03:14:38" id="L1242"/> We've applied it to our Primus Epic (indiscernible) cockpit down in the general aviation. <Sync time="03:14:44" id="L1243"/> I think it helps us put the technologists coming from the inside together with the customer and his needs from the outside so we will make better decisions. <Sync time="03:14:53" id="L1244"/> <br/> I talked to some of the engineers that have been here forever. <Sync time="03:14:56" id="L1245"/> It's like there was a point in time a long time ago where we used to try to win everything and then it would end up being an engineering problem to figure out how to fit all of that into the resource requirements. <Sync time="03:15:09" id="L1246"/> I think this is about deciding earlier what we really want to do and what makes a difference to the customer, and not just making those trade-offs at the end. <Sync time="03:15:20" id="L1247"/> <br/> To conclude, I am back to one of the charts I had earlier. <Sync time="03:15:23" id="L1248"/> I think we have great technology and we're getting better at putting it in the right applications that are best for both our customers and our shareholders. <Sync time="03:15:33" id="L1249"/> We are everywhere, and so we have to be decisive about that. <Sync time="03:15:38" id="L1250"/> We are using tools to get better. <Sync time="03:15:40" id="L1251"/> We're closer to our customers. <Sync time="03:15:42" id="L1252"/> We have a great backlog. <Sync time="03:15:43" id="L1253"/> It means we have to make good decisions about what we put in that backlog. <Sync time="03:15:48" id="L1254"/> We have a history of execution, and we've made our business much better but we're not done. <Sync time="03:15:55" id="L1255"/> I think we have great tools for growing in the future. <Sync time="03:15:57" id="L1256"/> <br/> So we are actually past the bottom, feeling good about the future. <Sync time="03:16:02" id="L1257"/> The only question is, what's the angle? <Sync time="03:16:05" id="L1258"/> We think it's a little premature to get too excited, but the next couple of years will be much better. <Sync time="03:16:14" id="L1259"/> Thank you.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="dangallagher"><Sync time="03:16:14" id="L1260"/> Thanks a lot, Bob. <Sync time="03:16:15" id="L1261"/> We have time for just a couple of questions. <Sync time="03:16:18" id="L1262"/> I think you had your hand up first.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="03:16:24" id="L1263"/> Bob, could you walk us through the margin dynamics, which you didn't spend a lot of time on? <Sync time="03:16:29" id="L1264"/> When I think about flat margins in the face of your comments and Dave's comments on the positive changes that are happening in the commercial aerospace market -- could you talk about the impact of the intellectual property that you had? <Sync time="03:16:43" id="L1265"/> You're not going to have gains. <Sync time="03:16:45" id="L1266"/> What's the technology? <Sync time="03:16:46" id="L1267"/> <br/> I guess also on the ERP implementation, is that roughly $50 million cost going to be absorbed solely this year? <Sync time="03:16:54" id="L1268"/> Do you bake it out over the next couple of years? <Sync time="03:16:57" id="L1269"/> <br/> Then, I guess lastly, with 40 percent of the business in aftermarket, is it fair to say that you're actually deriving more of your profit from, say, I guess discretionary spend from airlines related to the aftermarket, as opposed to flight hours?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="roberjohnson"><Sync time="03:17:14" id="L1270"/> Wow, that's a question (LAUGHTER).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="03:17:18" id="L1271"/> Could you repeat the question? (LAUGHTER).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="roberjohnson"><Sync time="03:17:27" id="L1272"/> First of all, we're not putting things on our balance sheet. <Sync time="03:17:33" id="L1273"/> So, what we are spending on the Information Systems and the SAP, we are writing it all off and it will benefit us and probably start to benefit us in '05 for all of those places where we put it. <Sync time="03:17:45" id="L1274"/> In fact, in our Human Resource process this year, we're looking at all those places where we can have centers of excellence and eliminate all of the duplications in all of the places. <Sync time="03:17:55" id="L1275"/> So we're going to get a -- in fact, when we decided to spend that money, we looked at things that had much less than a two-year payback. <Sync time="03:18:03" id="L1276"/> In fact, most of them had one year. <Sync time="03:18:04" id="L1277"/> We're going to spend money this year and we're going to get it back fairly quick, and we're not spreading it out over time. <Sync time="03:18:11" id="L1278"/> <br/> To your other question, while I feel better about the industry, I also recognize they are in the middle of a reconstruction. <Sync time="03:18:18" id="L1279"/> First of all, yields are not very good. <Sync time="03:18:23" id="L1280"/> There are some people who are winning now who have lower cost structure, but there's an awful lot of work to do in this industry in the Legacy carriers, which I remind us are most carriers, you know, a big piece of our volume that still have to go through that change process. <Sync time="03:18:38" id="L1281"/> They are going to have some battles. <Sync time="03:18:41" id="L1282"/> <br/> I will also remind us that fuel prices are up. <Sync time="03:18:43" id="L1283"/> So I don't think there are any purchasing managers who have been released. <Sync time="03:18:46" id="L1284"/> They are certainly not going to be able to reach back and build up their inventory again, and I think there are an awful lot of constraints on them still about the rates they but. <Sync time="03:18:57" id="L1285"/> <br/> So, while I think flying hours are going to be up 5 percent, I don't think that necessarily translates -- in the short-term -- into 5 percent more spare parts purchases. <Sync time="03:19:07" id="L1286"/> <br/> I think there is also a shift going on here around when the work is done. <Sync time="03:19:12" id="L1287"/> The one interesting item that happens here is as the airlines outsource work and it comes to me, I used to sell the spare parts ahead of time; now, I incorporate the spare parts in the repair so there's also a time lag. <Sync time="03:19:28" id="L1288"/> <br/> So, I think that we're still under some pressure; there are things that are working that down. <Sync time="03:19:34" id="L1289"/> We had a great year in intellectual property (inaudible). <Sync time="03:19:40" id="L1290"/> I'd like to continue that but you know, that isn't something that we can plan on. <Sync time="03:19:47" id="L1291"/> I think the Information Technology is an investment in our future. <Sync time="03:19:50" id="L1292"/> <br/> We are also trying to have fewer plants. <Sync time="03:19:53" id="L1293"/> So I'm trying to make a supply chain that's more efficient and so, you know, there's a cost of change there. <Sync time="03:20:02" id="L1294"/> I am optimistic but I think we have to have a little balance in the (indiscernible) and I don't think people are going to build new airplanes at a higher rate until sometime late in '05, certainly in '06. <Sync time="03:20:18" id="L1295"/> You know, we will get a little bit of benefit earlier than that but not in '04.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:20:25" id="L1296"/> We'd like a shorter question!</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:20:26" id="L1297"/> Did I get it all? <Sync time="03:20:27" id="L1298"/> I think I got most of it. <Sync time="03:20:28" id="L1299"/> <br/> Unidentified Audience Member; <Sync time="03:20:33" id="L1300"/> First, Bob, you had a couple of killer apps over the last couple of years. <Sync time="03:20:38" id="L1301"/> For example, enhanced proximity warning system, which really drove the business in a big way. <Sync time="03:20:43" id="L1302"/> So first, could you talk about a couple of the applications, either driven by FAA mandates, that you could see on the horizon that are going to drive the business? <Sync time="03:20:53" id="L1303"/> I mean, because you clearly have parts of the real estate of the cockpit that no one else owns but you. <Sync time="03:20:58" id="L1304"/> <br/> The second thing is could you talk for a moment about what could cause you to miss your plan? <Sync time="03:21:03" id="L1305"/> Because, I mean, we all kind of look here and say, you are lowballing a little bit. (multiple speakers).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="roberjohnson"><Sync time="03:21:11" id="L1306"/> I will answer the first question! <Sync time="03:21:14" id="L1307"/> First of all, we're trying to take some of those technologies -- and we get the news people to do ads for us, but this auto recovery -- you know, we still have a terrorist issue here and while I think we've done a lot of things to make it much harder, knowing where things are and determining there are no-fly zones -- because we're certainly able to work with the flight systems and the flight controls to take the plane away from those areas, even if -- and to give the control, after we are past that, back to the pilot. <Sync time="03:21:51" id="L1308"/> So there's some work there. <Sync time="03:21:53" id="L1309"/> That is very well received by people who are trying to keep us safe. <Sync time="03:21:58" id="L1310"/> We're going to have to work through that, but that's taking that technology and growing it. <Sync time="03:22:02" id="L1311"/> <br/> Knowing where everything is also, there are a number of incidents that occur and almost occur around runways and around airports, so there's a lot better information that can happen from that. <Sync time="03:22:16" id="L1312"/> <br/> There is the integration, as I said, of this surveillance equipment, which now are separate units that can be put into one and integrated. <Sync time="03:22:25" id="L1313"/> I think another example is the Primus Epic. <Sync time="03:22:28" id="L1314"/> A lot of the ability of getting different components and systems, different parts of the brain, to work together as an innovative brain happens in the Primus Epic. <Sync time="03:22:38" id="L1315"/> I think there are people who are saying, how can we do that (inaudible)? <Sync time="03:22:42" id="L1316"/> So, we're trying to take those technologies and move them into new spaces. <Sync time="03:22:47" id="L1317"/> I think there are applications there. <Sync time="03:22:49" id="L1318"/> <br/> I also think that we haven't seen a lot more mandates in the short-term because they are a set of priorities and there's also financial condition of the customers. <Sync time="03:22:59" id="L1319"/> But I think as the economy gets better and the financial balance sheets of our customers get better and we can move up this security thing which has started to happen, there will be opportunities for additional mandates. <Sync time="03:23:12" id="L1320"/> We have a very close working relationship with the FAA in terms of getting these new technologies into place; we are almost partners (inaudible), so we are excited about that. <Sync time="03:23:26" id="L1321"/> <br/> The second question is, you know, there are these same forces working against us. <Sync time="03:23:31" id="L1322"/> We have still a troubled industry that doesn't have cash; it has the yield issue. <Sync time="03:23:37" id="L1323"/> I think that's the downward pressure -- other than some extraordinary events that none of us want (inaudible) predict. <Sync time="03:23:45" id="L1324"/> <br/> On the plus side, I think the good thing is the industry has practiced some constraint. <Sync time="03:23:50" id="L1325"/> By now, in every other economic cycle, we would have had airlines buying aircraft in advance of their need and we would have heated up the whole supply chain. <Sync time="03:24:01" id="L1326"/> So I think we've learned some patience and we're practicing that, and I think we will have a better industry if we get the balance sheets right with our customers.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:24:11" id="L1327"/> We will take one more Aerospace question and then we will open it up to the wider group.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="03:24:17" id="L1328"/> Bob, on Page 31, if you add up your program revenue potential, '04 through '08, and if you were to -- this is defense and space here. <Sync time="03:24:26" id="L1329"/> Did you capture all of it? <Sync time="03:24:27" id="L1330"/> It imputes to something like 30 percent topline growth per year, average annual. <Sync time="03:24:33" id="L1331"/> So what is the practical amount, firstly? <Sync time="03:24:36" id="L1332"/> <br/> Secondly, within your major business areas within Arrow, what do you think roughly are your marketshares? <Sync time="03:24:42" id="L1333"/> Where, based on all of the programs and so forth, do you think you have opportunity to make the most gains?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="roberjohnson"><Sync time="03:24:50" id="L1334"/> In many of the commercial areas, we have very positive margins here (inaudible). <Sync time="03:24:57" id="L1335"/> I think the places where we are trying to go are where the industry is moving and requires more of our technology. <Sync time="03:25:07" id="L1336"/> So what you just added up is the sweet spot. <Sync time="03:25:11" id="L1337"/> I mean, when someone wants to take all old technologies that require a lot more people to fight wars and protect nations and fight the terrorism thing, it's about knowing more; it's about integrating space; it's about having the ability to do this with fewer people, but it's also about reducing the speed at which that information is captured, processed, sorted, and a decision made. <Sync time="03:25:42" id="L1338"/> So I think what you see people in the defense (indiscernible) is integrating all of that, integrating it across services. <Sync time="03:25:50" id="L1339"/> Whereas these all used to be separate activities that weren't easily or facilitously (ph) integrated, I think that's the focus. <Sync time="03:25:58" id="L1340"/> So, that's where our technology is. <Sync time="03:26:01" id="L1341"/> We won't win all of those things but we will win a lot of them. <Sync time="03:26:05" id="L1342"/> And so I see, over the next period of time, in the commercial markets, that's about making things better, lowering the costs so people can have healthy businesses but huge technology advances. <Sync time="03:26:20" id="L1343"/> I go from the Defense and Space side, I see where technology makes a difference and is needed. <Sync time="03:26:26" id="L1344"/> That's where we will play. <Sync time="03:26:27" id="L1345"/> So, I think we will have -- we have had, for the last few years, a higher growth rate in the defensive space. <Sync time="03:26:33" id="L1346"/> I don't think those are short-term transformation processes. <Sync time="03:26:37" id="L1347"/> I think that's 10 or 20 years and I think you go there and stay there. <Sync time="03:26:42" id="L1348"/> So, having that technology now puts us in a great place. <Sync time="03:26:45" id="L1349"/> I think we will have higher growth rates on the defensive space side than we will commercially over the next five to six years.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="03:27:00" id="L1350"/> (inaudible) what do you think you (inaudible)?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:27:03" id="L1351"/> I think it's a guess. (LAUGHTER). <Sync time="03:27:06" id="L1352"/> All right. <Sync time="03:27:07" id="L1353"/> Dave will want me to win them all but cut that in half or cut that in a third because there's a lot of players there. <Sync time="03:27:18" id="L1354"/> I feel very positive about that because it stays. <Sync time="03:27:23" id="L1355"/> I also like places where technology is ahead because I stay of being a commodity. <Sync time="03:27:29" id="L1356"/> Now, I'm a long way from being a commodity but I think that technology helps differentiate us.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:27:37" id="L1357"/> What we will do now is bring down all the presenters. <Sync time="03:27:39" id="L1358"/> We have about 20 minutes left for overall Q&amp;A. <Sync time="03:27:43" id="L1359"/> All of you come on down. <Sync time="03:27:49" id="L1360"/> <br/> You have everybody. <Sync time="03:28:01" id="L1361"/> What questions do we have? <Sync time="03:28:09" id="L1362"/> We will try to get to everyone. <Sync time="03:28:12" id="L1363"/> Brian, I think it's your first question of the day.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedaudiencemember"><Sync time="03:28:16" id="L1364"/> Hi, Dave. <Sync time="03:28:19" id="L1365"/> I'm going to ask a direct question that you can answer incorrectly. <Sync time="03:28:22" id="L1366"/> Just looking at your overall Specialty Materials segment, obviously, you've got some really good businesses in your (indiscernible) like (inaudible) some other things you really wouldn't want. <Sync time="03:28:34" id="L1367"/> Even though some of those businesses individually are good businesses, two or three or four years out, when things are going better, margins are back in double digits, somebody walks up to you and says 6, 6.5 times EBITDA. <Sync time="03:28:48" id="L1368"/> Any reason to hold the whole portfolio when you think about all the pain it causes every few years?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:28:54" id="L1369"/> I think you always have to look at stuff over time. <Sync time="03:28:56" id="L1370"/> Who knows how we will look at something three years from now or five years from now. <Sync time="03:29:00" id="L1371"/> I would say, though, that one of the advantages of being a multi-industry company is that you have a lot more avenues for growth; you're not just betting on one place. <Sync time="03:29:11" id="L1372"/> One of the things I like about our portfolio of businesses is that we've got a bunch of places that we can grow. <Sync time="03:29:17" id="L1373"/> There's a bunch of places where things could develop and we're planting seeds everywhere, because it's tough to say, geez, those are the three seeds we want to bet on and that's it! <Sync time="03:29:26" id="L1374"/> Instead, we've got 30 or 40 different ones to play, a number of them in Specialty Materials, so it's tough to say how things are going to evolve. <Sync time="03:29:33" id="L1375"/> I'm not ready to predict that one. <Sync time="03:29:35" id="L1376"/> I will say if all of those core businesses that we have in Specialty Materials are pretty darn good and the growth prospects for them are excellent, to have a $1.5 billion business that grows at the kind of rate I think Nance's can is not something to sneeze at. <Sync time="03:29:49" id="L1377"/> I like it.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:29:50" id="L1378"/> Any more questions? <Sync time="03:29:53" id="L1379"/> Scott Davis.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="scottdavis"><Sync time="03:29:59" id="L1380"/> To Bob Johnson, an aerospace question. <Sync time="03:30:02" id="L1381"/> There's been a couple of your customers have commented recently that they've had some problems with your avionics products; <Sync time="03:30:08" id="L1382"/> Embraer is one that I think is fairly high profile. <Sync time="03:30:11" id="L1383"/> Can you just comment on, give some color to what the problem is and kind of how far along you are in fixing this problem?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="roberjohnson"><Sync time="03:30:23" id="L1384"/> First of all, I think it's fixed. <Sync time="03:30:25" id="L1385"/> The problem is never the customers' problem. <Sync time="03:30:28" id="L1386"/> So, let's say that. <Sync time="03:30:30" id="L1387"/> <br/> I think what is really happening -- I will make an analogy. <Sync time="03:30:33" id="L1388"/> Remember SAP started making IT systems for companies and it took a while; at the beginning, it wasn't right. <Sync time="03:30:44" id="L1389"/> I think if you look at them now they are successful because both themselves and the customer made a conversion to understand what the job -- what the complications of doing it. <Sync time="03:30:55" id="L1390"/> We are really making a final (indiscernible) for an airplane and that is a partnership. <Sync time="03:31:03" id="L1391"/> What we had to learn was that it was the aircraft design that is changing. <Sync time="03:31:08" id="L1392"/> During its birthing, the spinal cord has to be adjusted. <Sync time="03:31:13" id="L1393"/> While we have the right technology, we weren't anticipating all of the changes in the aircraft body that had to be done. <Sync time="03:31:22" id="L1394"/> Once we got that down, we got it made. <Sync time="03:31:26" id="L1395"/> <br/> So, I think that takes an even closer relationship. <Sync time="03:31:31" id="L1396"/> What we've learned is the aircraft's body is going to change and we've still got to get the aircraft done on time. <Sync time="03:31:40" id="L1397"/> So it's not a technology; the technology is great. <Sync time="03:31:42" id="L1398"/> <br/> It's also about controlling the process because lots of people want to have different things in their spinal cord, and so we've had to put some control processes in so that not everybody has us going back into the room to make a new spinal cord every day. <Sync time="03:31:59" id="L1399"/> <br/> So I think those were learning processes, but it was never about the technology. <Sync time="03:32:04" id="L1400"/> So, our job here is to get closer to the customer and build in the fact that the aircraft is going to have modifications in its design, and we need to build those into our plans.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="scottdavis"><Sync time="03:32:17" id="L1401"/> A second question -- we've heard some that some third-party parts suppliers have made some inroads into the industry, not necessarily just your products but some competitors. <Sync time="03:32:27" id="L1402"/> Is that a real competitive threat, or is it just noise? <Sync time="03:32:30" id="L1403"/> Is there an impact on the potential price down the road from the third-party parts suppliers?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="roberjohnson"><Sync time="03:32:35" id="L1404"/> Listen, I think that if people can enter this industry and do things with a valuable customer, that is fine. <Sync time="03:32:47" id="L1405"/> In our case, what we're doing is making sure that the intellectual property of our company isn't being misused in that process. <Sync time="03:32:59" id="L1406"/> We have to do this too, so I'm getting into the third-party repair business. <Sync time="03:33:04" id="L1407"/> I used to put new parts in and then I started repairing my parts for my customers. <Sync time="03:33:12" id="L1408"/> Now, I'm repairing other people's parts for my customers. <Sync time="03:33:16" id="L1409"/> So helping the customer be successful and make things cost less and less (inaudible) that's (inaudible) for anybody. <Sync time="03:33:23" id="L1410"/> So I have great intellectual property and I want to use it for my shareholders and my customers, not other people. <Sync time="03:33:33" id="L1411"/> So I think it's just a matter of tightening it up. <Sync time="03:33:34" id="L1412"/> I think they've been here forever and I think they will be here and if that helps us all be better at what we do, that's fine. <Sync time="03:33:41" id="L1413"/> <br/> I don't think of it as a threat; <Sync time="03:33:43" id="L1414"/> I think it's an opportunity.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:33:47" id="L1415"/> First question today for David Bleustein.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidbleustein"><Sync time="03:33:51" id="L1416"/> Really a question for Dave Anderson. <Sync time="03:33:54" id="L1417"/> With the bottom of your cycles arguably behind you and your pension now well funded and your cash needs for asbestos fairly well-defined and a favorable cash flow outlook, how would you define the optimal capital structure for Honeywell? <Sync time="03:34:10" id="L1418"/> How long do you think it'll take you to get there?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:34:13" id="L1419"/> Can you hear me? <Sync time="03:34:15" id="L1420"/> Well, we are pretty comfortable with the capital structures that we have today. <Sync time="03:34:21" id="L1421"/> We showed numbers earlier; both Dave and I showed numbers that showed the net debt to cap. <Sync time="03:34:26" id="L1422"/> We are now down, as you know, below 20 percent but I think probably more meaningful numbers, numbers that Tassos (ph) would look at, for example, would be FFO to debt or debt to EBITDA. <Sync time="03:34:36" id="L1423"/> Those are comfortable with -- we are very comfortable with that in terms of where we are today and what the rating agencies view us and how we view ourselves in terms of the capacity and flexibility that we have. <Sync time="03:34:51" id="L1424"/> <br/> Going forward, I think we've had a chance to touch on that several times today -- is the focus on growing our strong businesses. <Sync time="03:34:59" id="L1425"/> That's really our priority. <Sync time="03:35:02" id="L1426"/> We've talked about both organic growth; we've talked about acquisition pursuit and the improvement -- tightening and upgrade that we have in the acquisition processes that we are deploying in the Company. <Sync time="03:35:14" id="L1427"/> So I don't think there's any magic number in terms of a desired capital structure. <Sync time="03:35:21" id="L1428"/> It's continued to maintain the strength and flexibility that we have today while utilizing the cash to grow our businesses, share repurchase, dividends, etc. -- no specific targets.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:35:39" id="L1429"/> Paula Abbotts (ph).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="paulaabbotts"><Sync time="03:35:41" id="L1430"/> This is for Dave Cote. <Sync time="03:35:44" id="L1431"/> I just was wondering if you could give us a sense on the acquisition pipeline. <Sync time="03:35:47" id="L1432"/> Is it full? <Sync time="03:35:48" id="L1433"/> What are the prices like for the deals that you are looking at?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidcote"><Sync time="03:35:53" id="L1434"/> Actually, we have an acquisition pipeline discussion about every six or seven weeks with each of the businesses just to look at what are those opportunities that seem to make sense for them or that they want to run to ground. <Sync time="03:36:06" id="L1435"/> Some things look like they get out of whack and we jump out of those. <Sync time="03:36:10" id="L1436"/> We're going to be extremely cautious about overpaying. <Sync time="03:36:13" id="L1437"/> For the ones that we have been able to complete, we are pretty well convinced we got them at a fair price and that's why the returns have been good. <Sync time="03:36:21" id="L1438"/> <br/> You know, we're constantly looking at ideas, some small, some big. <Sync time="03:36:27" id="L1439"/> They have to make sense financially and when they start to get out of whack, we jump out; we don't play. <Sync time="03:36:32" id="L1440"/> But so far, it's been reasonable.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:36:35" id="L1441"/> Harriet Baldwin, first question of the day.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="harribaldwin"><Sync time="03:36:40" id="L1442"/> (Multiple Speakers) -- you'd think you would be keeping score or something. <Sync time="03:36:48" id="L1443"/> Dave Anderson, can you talk about how Honeywell overall is doing on past due receivables and how critical that improvement is to the working cap generation for '04? <Sync time="03:37:01" id="L1444"/> And then back to the design for Six Sigma example on the thermostats -- talk about what investment, if any other than the design, was required to improve those cycle times -- new tooling, what have you?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:37:14" id="L1445"/> The past due trendline, Harriet, has come down. <Sync time="03:37:17" id="L1446"/> We've made progress that's consistent with the DSO progress I showed you earlier, when we showed the working capital trends. <Sync time="03:37:26" id="L1447"/> Dan, do you have the current DSO number in your mind?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:37:31" id="L1448"/> Yes, we went down about 1.5 points. <Sync time="03:37:32" id="L1449"/> We are down about 19 percent, I believe.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:37:36" id="L1450"/> So you would see that steady trendline. <Sync time="03:37:38" id="L1451"/> We showed you earlier that '02, '03, '04 trendline in terms of working capital percent, DSO and inventory turns. <Sync time="03:37:46" id="L1452"/> We would show similar positive numbers in terms of the DSO. <Sync time="03:37:50" id="L1453"/> That's a good question. <Sync time="03:37:52" id="L1454"/> <br/> Roger?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:37:54" id="L1455"/> Reasonable capital investment. <Sync time="03:37:56" id="L1456"/> We invested in new production lines to be able to make them in five minutes versus the five days that I referred to, not only in manufacturing equipment, but test equipment and what you would expect in making a high-volume electronics product. <Sync time="03:38:09" id="L1457"/> So, nothing out of the ordinary but it's still significant, given the volume.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:38:16" id="L1458"/> Next up, Tony Bowles (ph).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="tonybowles"><Sync time="03:38:19" id="L1459"/> I guess for either one of the Daves, could you talk a little bit about the potential timing for adding a new segment or platform to Honeywell and maybe some of the attributes that it would have to have to make it attractive to you, maybe some guidelines, certain things you wouldn't go into, certain things that would be attractive to you, that kind of a discussion?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:38:46" id="L1460"/> Sounds like a CEO question to me! (LAUGHTER).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:38:51" id="L1461"/> If we go back to what we said the base was for acquisitions and the importance of being able to understand the industry and understand what it is it that we're getting into, it depends, then, on how you define this new segment. <Sync time="03:39:08" id="L1462"/> Now, if you say, "Gee, Healthcare is growing. <Sync time="03:39:12" id="L1463"/> Healthcare looks like a great thing to be in; we need to go by a drug company." <Sync time="03:39:16" id="L1464"/> I would say, you're not going to see us do something like that. <Sync time="03:39:19" id="L1465"/> It makes no sense for us. <Sync time="03:39:21" id="L1466"/> We don't know anything about it; we would have to pay a huge amount of money. <Sync time="03:39:23" id="L1467"/> When we talk about the cost synergies, there would be almost none. <Sync time="03:39:27" id="L1468"/> You would be extremely unlikely to see us do something like that. <Sync time="03:39:30" id="L1469"/> <br/> If you start looking at, say, a Siesta, and you say, "Gee, would the (indiscernible) Dick Roger was talking about, the fire and security, the environmental controls, and how those are base technologies that can take you into a lot of things" -- so you could probably acquire a company that is different than what we're doing today but akin to the technologies that we have, so that you could expect the corporate synergies, in addition to the normal business synergies, that would make sense. <Sync time="03:39:59" id="L1470"/> That would be the way we would look at it. <Sync time="03:40:01" id="L1471"/> So you are unlikely to see us go and add something where we are making Band-Aids or something; it just wouldn't fit with how we want to look at the Company and how we could add value.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:40:10" id="L1472"/> Don MacDougall.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="donmacdougall"><Sync time="03:40:14" id="L1473"/> This question might be for Dave Anderson. <Sync time="03:40:20" id="L1474"/> Going back to the slide on cash flow and looking forward, I know we went out to '05 on some of the moving variables in cash. <Sync time="03:40:29" id="L1475"/> Focusing on asbestos, if you could maybe take us a few years out beyond '05, just how hard the numbers are that are in the forecast and talk about how that decays? <Sync time="03:40:41" id="L1476"/> <br/> Then a related question, as the taxes come back up, you exhaust your NOLs. <Sync time="03:40:47" id="L1477"/> Is it your assumption that the decline in the asbestos payouts would more than offset the increased taxes as you looked into the next few years?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:40:57" id="L1478"/> Don, with respect to the first piece of that, on the asbestos, the key thing that's calibrated will be known but certainly calibrated is the NARCO piece of that. <Sync time="03:41:12" id="L1479"/> In other words, as part of the Trust agreement and as part of the settlement with plaintiffs, we have a cap in those out years in that '06, '07, '08 period. <Sync time="03:41:23" id="L1480"/> I think, Peter, that's about $130 million. <Sync time="03:41:27" id="L1481"/> Does that sound about right?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="peterkreindler"><Sync time="03:41:27" id="L1482"/> (inaudible) payout mostly over three years, some as long as five years. <Sync time="03:41:38" id="L1483"/> But the cap on futures claims, I think, at its greatest level is $130 million.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:41:44" id="L1484"/> Right, so you've got a tail, as Peter is describing, on the currents and then you've got a cap on the future. <Sync time="03:41:51" id="L1485"/> So these are future projections; they may not be precisely '06, '07, '08, but in that five-year planning horizon, we should we should achieve -- with the Trust, we should achieve that level. <Sync time="03:42:05" id="L1486"/> <br/> As we mentioned today, we have the reserve for the currents on Bendix, on the friction materials business, which we think is adequate for the currents. <Sync time="03:42:15" id="L1487"/> Then again, going forward, we have got both insurance as well as we've got the operating performance of the business, which we think will be adequate in terms of going forward, in terms of the coverage of those liabilities for the time frame in which we can envision it. <Sync time="03:42:30" id="L1488"/> Again, it's a dynamic thing because there's a lot of volatility, variability in terms of what we've experienced historically in terms of the number of claims on Bendix. <Sync time="03:42:40" id="L1489"/> <br/> With respect to the crossover between the cash claim, if you will, or cash requirements of asbestos and then getting out of the NOLs, exhausting the NOLs and being back into U.S. cash tax paying period -- I haven't done the math to do that precisely to tell you where that crossover point would be and the amount of that. <Sync time="03:43:02" id="L1490"/> <br/> I would say that, as we look forward in the analysis that we've done of cash flow from our businesses, other cash requirements, going forward, we see more than enough to fuel the growth -- the kind of growth that we've talked about today, to fund the strategies that we've talked about today, as well as to maintain (indiscernible) returns to shareholders either through dividend to create share repurchase or any combination. <Sync time="03:43:30" id="L1491"/> So, we are really confident in terms of the outlook for the overall cash picture.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:43:34" id="L1492"/> For what it's worth, Don, (inaudible) -- (technical difficulty) -- (indiscernible) he added a vault to his conference room just to hold future cash flows! (LAUGHTER).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:43:46" id="L1493"/> Okay, Howard?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="howarrubel"><Sync time="03:43:49" id="L1494"/> You have some assets for sale, and this goes to kind to kind of an earnings -- reported earnings question. <Sync time="03:43:56" id="L1495"/> We saw it in this last quarter where you had some nets and if we look forward, you're going to have some additional nets, Dave, that as you sell some assets that are going to generate some gains. <Sync time="03:44:07" id="L1496"/> How are you going to reinvest that gain? <Sync time="03:44:10" id="L1497"/> What do you think the right approach to do that is, to communicate that?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:44:16" id="L1498"/> From my standpoint, the strategy is going to be no different than what we were talking about earlier today. <Sync time="03:44:21" id="L1499"/> The first priority of any gains, any cash we generate is going to be making sure that we invest right in our businesses. <Sync time="03:44:27" id="L1500"/> Then we're going to be looking at dividends, stock buyback and acquisitions. <Sync time="03:44:32" id="L1501"/> That doesn't really change the mix of cash deployment strategies we look at.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="howarrubel"><Sync time="03:44:37" id="L1502"/> (inaudible question - microphone inaccessible).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:44:55" id="L1503"/> I think that probably the best way -- it depends on what happens, what occurs. <Sync time="03:45:01" id="L1504"/> Who knows what circumstances look like when we get there? <Sync time="03:45:04" id="L1505"/> So, it's tough to predict right now if there are going to be gains and if there are, do you deploy them? <Sync time="03:45:11" id="L1506"/> Do they just fall through? <Sync time="03:45:12" id="L1507"/> It is tough to know.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:45:17" id="L1508"/> Chuck Harris (ph).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="chuckharris"><Sync time="03:45:20" id="L1509"/> Two questions. <Sync time="03:45:21" id="L1510"/> I guess this is for Dave Anderson. <Sync time="03:45:23" id="L1511"/> The first one is, could we go back to sort of working capital management and particularly, when the aerospace cycle -- if and when it starts to pick in the '05 timeframe -- you know, every unit, the very high-value unit -- how do you keep the focus on working capital and inventory turns and everything else in that type of an environment and actually continue -- I mean, is that a point in time where we flip the working capital into a use for a couple of years because that's inevitably what's going to happen, or is there something else there?</Turn>
<Turn speaker="davidanderson"><Sync time="03:45:55" id="L1512"/> Well, we've targeted continuous improvement and Bob talked about the fact that we've invested through the cycle. <Sync time="03:46:02" id="L1513"/> The investment has not just taken the form of products and technology and training, etc.; it's also taken the form of lean implementation and improvement in inventory management processes. <Sync time="03:46:18" id="L1514"/> <br/> The other thing I think, Bob, that you had up there was a targeted benefit contribution from the SAP implementation, from the ERP and digitization. <Sync time="03:46:29" id="L1515"/> I think that was probably a P&amp;L contribution but the reality is there's a very significant working capital, operating capital benefit to that as well. <Sync time="03:46:38" id="L1516"/> <br/> I think the other thing you mentioned was some facilities review as part of your overall supply chain management. <Sync time="03:46:45" id="L1517"/> So, when we look at the kind of in queue (ph) underway and planned initiatives to support working capital, one of the key points is that we've made a significant emphasis around that during this period when market conditions had been very tough. <Sync time="03:47:04" id="L1518"/> So we really aim to be in very, very good position and continue -- and we've targeted that for '04. <Sync time="03:47:10" id="L1519"/> We haven't shown you figures for '05 but we've targeted for '04 despite the revenue growth to continue to have working capital as an important contributor to cash.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="chuckharris"><Sync time="03:47:20" id="L1520"/> Following up on a broader question, this is really going back to Dave Bleustein's question. <Sync time="03:47:27" id="L1521"/> You know, from what I -- not having a balance sheet target, per se, of what the best capital structure ought to be, it sort of leaves me sitting here thinking one of two things. <Sync time="03:47:39" id="L1522"/> Either that there's a liability out there that you are worried about that is unquantifiable, be it that the asbestos thing isn't really as nailed down as tight as you need it to be and this gives you the flexibility with the rating agencies to do whatever you want -- or -- I can't even think of an or!</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:47:59" id="L1523"/> The way I think about it is that, first of all, we start in this 2004 period with a healthy balance sheet, good cash on hand, lots flexibility. <Sync time="03:48:15" id="L1524"/> But also, we've been fairly specific in terms of where we want to go, what we want to do with that cash. <Sync time="03:48:21" id="L1525"/> <br/> Going forward, we have to anticipate that there are going to be opportunities that we don't foresee today, so we want to maintain some degree of flexibility around that. <Sync time="03:48:30" id="L1526"/> We like the A credit rating. <Sync time="03:48:32" id="L1527"/> We think that's an important attribute of the Company. <Sync time="03:48:36" id="L1528"/> We would like to maintain that. <Sync time="03:48:38" id="L1529"/> So (indiscernible) is more on EBITDA -- debt to EBITDA, if you will. <Sync time="03:48:44" id="L1530"/> It's more on FFO to debt (indiscernible) things again that taunts us is looking at and that we're looking at and that we're monitoring. <Sync time="03:48:51" id="L1531"/> Frankly again, as you look through the planned (ph) period, things that we want to do, things that we want to execute the way we want to growth the business -- we're pretty comfortable with that. <Sync time="03:49:01" id="L1532"/> So giving you a debt-to-capital number and saying that is the target number I think would be a little bit misleading.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="chuckharris"><Sync time="03:49:06" id="L1533"/> (inaudible) is within the A rating that you have, you're still, by most definitions, either a debt to EBITDA calculation, a debt to total capital -- about every calculation you can think of, you are well within the boundaries of a single A credit and well above that, for all practical purposes, to give you the flexibility, particularly given the cash flow attributes that you say the Company will have over the next several years. <Sync time="03:49:29" id="L1534"/> I mean, it's going to be difficult, even if you want to, to go out and spend that kind of money that quickly to create any inflexibility unless you do something extraordinarily large (indiscernible) does the subliminal message that there's going to be large acquisition. <Sync time="03:49:42" id="L1535"/> You can't do that many small acquisitions, I don't think. <Sync time="03:49:46" id="L1536"/> I'm just trying to working it through. (LAUGHTER).</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:49:50" id="L1537"/> I think we get the question at this point!</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:49:54" id="L1538"/> We had the same conversation a year ago; we had the same conversation about 18 months ago. <Sync time="03:49:59" id="L1539"/> There's been no big, bad thing that has happened in either direction. <Sync time="03:50:04" id="L1540"/> I just say, look at some of the history here. <Sync time="03:50:07" id="L1541"/> As we said from the beginning, the money is not burning a hole in our pocket; we like having a single A credit rating and more companies had been burned by blowing cash than by keeping it. <Sync time="03:50:18" id="L1542"/> I just think it makes sense for us to think smartly about how we want to use the money. <Sync time="03:50:22" id="L1543"/> Dave is in the same (indiscernible) and so are our business leaders.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="unidentifiedcompanyrepresentative"><Sync time="03:50:24" id="L1544"/> I think realistically, too, as you look at earnings growth, earnings momentum, you look at share repurchase opportunities, associate that with requirements to hold shares constant. <Sync time="03:50:39" id="L1545"/> You look at -- it's not unreasonable, I don't think, with the set of businesses we have today, to do small and medium, both build core and add adjacent acquisitions that could total $1 billion a year. <Sync time="03:50:52" id="L1546"/> So I mean, there's lots of smart ways to execute around the cash while maintaining that credit rating. <Sync time="03:50:59" id="L1547"/> So that's really what's in our mind.</Turn>
<Turn speaker="moderator"><Sync time="03:51:02" id="L1548"/> It's four o'clock. <Sync time="03:51:03" id="L1549"/> We're going to finish on time. <Sync time="03:51:04" id="L1550"/> Now, Dave, the rest of the presenters and the rest of his leadership team are looking forward to talking to you on the third floor where we have cocktails and some hors d'oeuvres set up, so I hope you can stick around for awhile. <Sync time="03:51:14" id="L1551"/> Thank you! <br/></Turn>
</Section>
</Episode>
</Trans>
</EventTranscript>
